You're getting out today, huh?
That's what we heard.
Why are you so quiet, huh?
Who was all mouth the other day
when I confronted you in the showers?
Lost my yard privileges 'cause of you.
Hey, it's Stef,
I'm either working or avoiding your...
Hi, Lena?
I'm David.
Uh... where's Bill?
I just spoke with him, he's
supposed to meet with me here.
Um, yeah, Bill. One of his cases...
Well, a kid in one of
his foster homes OD'd,
so he had to rush to the hospital.
- Oh my God.
- Yeah, it's terrible.
- I take it he told you about Callie?
- Yes.
Yes, well, it seems that she's been having
a few issues with male
authority figures, of late.
- Which is...
- That's why he thought of us.
- Right.
- So, she got into a fight with her foster father?
And damaged some of his property,
which is how she landed here in juvie.
Damaged his property. Uh... Wow. David...
Bill and I have known each
other for a very long time,
and he's been a friend of the family
ever since he placed the twins with us,
but I cannot bring someone
violent into my house.
I've got my own kids to think about.
No, this was just a one time thing.
Listen, it'll only just be for a few weeks.
- Oh my goodness.
- Um...
When the kids get out, some of the other
inmates get jealous and pick fights.
- One second. One second?
- But...
Callie? Callie, hi.
I'm David, I work with Bill
at Child Protective Services.
Um... where's Jude? Do
you know where he is?
- I don't know...
- I need to speak to him.
Where's Bill? Why isn't Bill here?
We'll have to talk about that later.
I just, I don't understand
why I can't talk to Jude.
That's enough. I don't know
what you're talking about.
Callie, this is Lena. Lena, Callie.
I guess I could take her
to one of the group homes.
It's just for a few weeks, right?
Ok.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com
So, Mariana and Jesus were
in the foster program, too.
They came to us about eight years ago,
and we formally adopted
them five years ago.
- Foster system sucks.
- Jesus...
He's right. It kind of does.
- Ok.
- What happened to your face?
- Get in a fight?
- Uh...
Callie's kind of had a rough day.
So, how about we cool
it with the third degree.
Is there... where's the bathroom?
Yeah, it's right through
there. You'll see it.
So... where'd she come from?
Um... I, I talked to Bill
from Child Protective
Services, you remember him?
To talk to him about something and he...
you know, he was in a bind with Callie.
And he needed some place for her to stay.
She's had a rough time lately, so, I really
need you guys to be extra nice to her.
- Please?
- What were you talking to Bill about?
Guess.
All right, so I was going to
wait till everyone was home
to talk to you guys
about this. Have a seat.
I was calling to find out when we could
set up a meeting with your birth mom.
I thought you would be more excited.
This is kind of all you've been
talking about for the last six months.
Yeah. Yeah, I know.
I did, just... I don't think so.
Did Jesus talk you out of this?
- Just because he doesn't want to go...
- Don't look at me.
No, I just... changed my mind is all.
Ok, so did you guys do your homework?
What? Why you gotta look at me like that?
Just 'cause you get straight
A's and you don't have to study?
Jesus, everyone has their strengths.
- Hey. Hey, guys.
- Hey! How was the audition?
It was good, it was
good. I made the finals.
Oh, my God!
- That's fantastic.
- It's not that big of a deal.
It is a huge deal. Are you kidding me?
That's like a 5,000 dollar
scholarship, isn't it?
- When is it?
- It's tomorrow and we're all going
So, homework right after school, please?
Who's this?
Oh, this is Callie.
She's going to be staying
with us for a little while.
Oh, ok. Staying with us.
Um, nice to meet you.
What about him?
What?
How'd you get him?
99 Cent Store? I mean,
they have everything there.
Um, Brandon is my partner Stephanie's
biological son from her previous marriage.
- Hey honey.
- Hi.
It smells great. Lasagna.
Delicious, thank you.
- How are you, honey?
- Good, how are you?
Hi babies!
What? Nobody told you our mom's a cop?
See, this is why no boys
ever want to come over.
- As it should be.
- So, you're dykes.
They prefer the term "people,"
but yeah, they're gay.
And he's the real son.
And who's this?
I tried calling you several times.
Yes, I know. You never left a message.
What was I going to say
in a message about this?
What do we know about this girl
that we're bringing into our house,
with our children? What
happened to her face?
She got beat up in juvie.
- In juvie? Lena...
- I know, I know!
I talked to Bill.
She's not violent, she's
not dangerous in any way.
- This was a one time thing.
- Honey, we can't save them all.
It's just for a few weeks.
I'm telling you, if you had been there,
and seen the way this girl looked at me.
Honey, I know you only did this
out of the goodness of your heart,
and I can't get mad at you for that, can I?
Oh, mushy.
I ought to... bring kids home more often.
Oh, please do not, 'cause any more kids,
it's gonna be like The
Brady Bunch around here,
and we're... we're definitely
not The Brady Bunch.
The curfew on school night is seven.
You must ask permission from Lena
or myself before leaving the house.
Also, you'll go to school
while you're staying here.
Lena is the Vice Principal of
Anchor Beach Charter School,
- All the kids go there...
- Where do I sleep?
Excuse me?
It's not my first time in a foster home.
Where do I sleep?
Let me show you.
One pillow or two?
Ok, I'll leave them both.
I left some towels for you in the
bathroom and do you have a toothbrush?
No, I don't have a toothbrush.
How would I have gotten a toothbrush?
Ok.
Callie, we're on your side.
You can take it down a notch, ok?
Yeah.
I noticed you were really upset when
you were talking to David earlier.
Who's Jude?
Look...
When I went into juvie...
Hey, here are some clothes
for you to sleep in.
Tonight, if you want to leave your
clothes outside of the bathroom,
I'll wash and make sure
they're clean for tomorrow, ok?
Good night.
You were saying?
You have that toothbrush?
__
Oh, hey, you guys know the rules.
- Ah, very good.
- Gracias, senor.
Hey, you two know that it's
not true what Callie said, huh?
You two are every bit as much
our kids as Brandon is, yes?
- We know.
- Miss Thing?
Ok.
- I love you, my babies.
- Good night.
Mm, 15 minutes till lights out, ok?
- Hey baby.
- Hey.
Hey. B, listen. Um...
I really need you to step up while
Callie is in this house, all right?
Um, I don't want to make
a big deal about this,
especially with Mariana and Jesus,
but between you and me, Callie
was in juvie for a little while.
Then what is she doing in the house?
She's fine.
Lena and I would not have her in this house
if she was not, you know that.
So, I just need you to, I don't know...
Ok. All right, well, I'll be sure to...
"I don't know" as much as I can.
Are you sure you're not
Lena's biological son?
I've got so much homework to do now,
Moby-Dick waits for no man.
Oh, which reminds me, do you need condoms?
- Oh, my God.
- You and Talya are using condoms, yeah?
Yeah, the door is right there.
What? Protect and serve. That's my job.
- Mom.
- Ok.
My little baby is
growing up. He's such a...
- Get out.
- ... handsome young man.
I needed some water.
Thank you.
Ok, so I've been thinking...
and I know how mad I would've been
if you would've made such a huge
decision without consulting me.
- I'm sorry.
- It's fine.
All right? I'm ok. She's not exactly the...
the warmest kid I've ever met.
I really appreciate you making the effort.
It means a lot to me.
Of course, my love.
You know, I just think that poor girl has
just been through so much.
I'm just really glad we can
give her a place to stay.
You know, that's safe.
- For now.
- For now...
As long as she doesn't mess
with our family. It's all good.
Now get off my side, please.
Ok, mama tiger.
Do you want to hear something strange?
Sure.
I talked to the twins about
arranging a visit with their
birth mom, like we talked about.
Mm-hm?
And now, neither one
of them wants to do it.
- Not even Mariana?
- Nope.
She says she's not ready.
Good.
Hey, hey baby, it's me.
Yeah, I'm out and I... I'm coming.
I promise, Jude. I just, I got
to figure out how to get there.
Did you take your pill, sweet knuckle head?
- I'm on it.
- Really? Like you're on the toast?
- Let's go, let's go.
- Thank you.
Whoa, whoa. I know you got a
sweater to go over that, baby.
- Yeah.
- Good girl.
Good morning, sunshine.
Orange juice on the table,
help yourself. Make yourself at home.
Ok, backpacks? Backpacks?
- Yes, I saw Mariana's.
- Can everyone give me a yes?
Jesus? Backpack. Where is it?
- Mm.
- Good job, baby, good job.
So, you nervous for tonight?
I'm not nervous, I got it.
You totally are.
It's all good.
I heard that pep talk...
Would you like some cream?
Uh, can I have some coffee, too?
No.
Hey Brandon, why don't
you show Callie around?
She's starting the day in Timothy's class.
You have your class list, Callie?
You're going to love
Timothy. He's a lot of fun.
You go to school here?
Yeah. Um...
So, Timothy's room...
it's over there, you'll find it ok, right?
I got like, 20 minutes before
class. So I wanted to go practice.
Practice for what?
The music finals for
the competition tonight.
- Right.
- All right. Well, see ya.
Hey, wait up!
- What is that?
- What? The song?
- Oh, I wrote it.
- You wrote it.
Yep, it's for the contest.
You need one classical piece,
and one original composition.
It's about the night Mom and Lena asked me
if it was ok for the twins
to come and live with us.
How is it about that?
Doesn't have any words.
Listen.
Ok, so...
That's me.
And...
These are my moms.
This is all of us. This is me, mom,
Lena, the twins...
See, how it all works better?
Nice.
Yeah... I don't know.
I still think it's missing something.
No, I like it.
Wait, they asked you if the
twins could move in with you?
Were you going to say no?
Nah, I mean,
I don't know, I figured
there was enough to go around.
Enough of what?
Everything.
Hey baby.
- Hey, what's up?
- How are you?
I'm good... how are you?
I'm good.
Who's this?
Uh, this is Callie. Callie, this is Talya.
She's going to be staying
with us for awhile.
- Welcome to Anchor Beach.
- Thanks.
She's actually in
Timothy's room with you, T.
So, if you want to... show her where it is.
Oh yeah, of course. But we should go.
Have fun.
Did he participate in
his own transformation?
Did he will it?
Did he want it to happen?
Or, was it something that happened to him?
How about you, Callie? Callie?
I know you haven't read
the material yet, but...
what would you do if you suddenly woke up
and found yourself living a nightmare.
- Hey.
- Hey, so...
I've been thinking and
I'm going to go with you.
- What?
- To meet Ana. I'll go with you, if you want.
But, you don't even want to meet her.
Yeah, I know.
Look, I told you, I don't think I'm ready.
Yeah, I know. That's why
I'm trying to go with you.
No, thank you.
Hey! Hey!
- Hi, what's your name?
- Aiden.
Aiden, right. Nice to meet you.
- Uh, you new here?
- Yeah. Yep. New girl.
Just moved here, actually.
I could really use
someone to show me around.
That can be arranged.
- You have a car, right?
- Yep.
Cool. Um, well, I was
actually thinking about
checking out San Ysidro this afternoon.
San Ysidro. Down by Tijuana?
Yeah, I hear it's cool there.
What? Are you like, looking
to party or something?
No...
I just have someone I need to see there.
Yeah...
No thanks. Good luck.
Hey, is there a Metro stop somewhere?
I'll be right back.
You going somewhere? Got to meet your pimp?
What is your problem?
Take too many of your brother's pills?
Don't worry, I'm not going to narc on you.
I mean, your mom's a
cop. That's got to suck.
I guess. So, are you leaving?
Don't worry. I'm not going to narc on you.
I just have some stuff
I've got to take care of.
Sorry, it's better if you don't know.
That way, if your mom... moms
start asking you questions...
Wait. If it were me,
I'd make sure to go out the back way.
Lena's office looks out
over the front entrance
and there's a bus stop
three blocks from here.
... very long list of people who
want to get involved with this school.
It's very parental driven, we
want the parents involved...
in the process. We want them...
We want them involved in every step...
- Real good, all right?
- Captain needs to see you.
Ok. All right guys, take
it easy. I'll see you later.
- Hey.
- Hey, you all right?
- Yeah.
- You're not going to cry, are you?
No, with all due respect, screw you.
- Well, Vasquez was a pain in my ass!
- Amen!
Sacramento can have him.
Right now, since both
of you are partnerless,
starting tomorrow, I'm going
to pair you up with Mike here.
- Ma'am.
- Is that a problem?
No, that's not a problem.
- May I ask why?
- I asked.
- You did?
- Is that cool?
Uh, can I have time to think about it?
- No.
- All right, I think it's very cool.
- Good.
- It's a great idea on your part.
- All right.
- Get out of my office.
Mike, it's not going to go well for me.
Hey. Hey, I need some money.
Um, rude much? No,
you've got your own money.
I left my wallet at home. Come on, I
didn't eat lunch. I'm really hungry.
- Too bad for you.
- I'm just going to take five bucks.
I promise, I'll pay you back tonight.
- Jesus, stop!
- What is this?
- Nothing.
- Where'd you get that?
Don't worry about it. Here...
Here's five dollars. Now
go eat and leave me alone.
- Who's that?
- I... I don't know.
Well, my parents are going
out of town this weekend.
- Oh yeah?
- You want to stay the night?
I'd have to sneak out.
Or, just tell them
you're staying with Aiden.
- Brandon... Hey.
- Yeah, hey.
- Do you want to come?
- Two seconds. Can you give me two seconds?
So, uh... where you going?
I've got some stuff to take care of.
Stuff to take care of? Like, right now?
- It's important.
- Ok.
You won't be able to take care
of it if you end up back in juvie.
I mean, my mom's a cop.
You seriously think she won't
track you down in a minute flat.
Can you just mind your own damn
business? Your whole freakin' family?
- We're just trying to help you.
- Stop.
Somebody's been calling me
from this number all day.
Hey.
Hey baby, it's me. What's going on?
What do you mean?
Jude, what are you saying?
Let me talk to Jude.
Put him back on the phone.
What's going on? Who was that?
Why are they calling my number?
I borrowed your phone last night.
I gotta go.
So, who was that? Was that like
your boyfriend or something?
- No.
- Then who was it?
How do they have my number, Callie?
- Who is it?
- It was my brother.
Whoa, whoa... let me call my mom.
- Stef?
- Yes, she's a cop.
- She can help.
- No cops.
- She's not like that.
- If you call your mom,
she's going to look in the system
and find all of these complaints
that my foster father made against me.
You're going to get me sent back to juvie,
and Jude is going to
be stuck in that house.
I gotta go.
Wait, didn't you have
that music thing tonight?
Uh, yeah. It's... don't worry about it.
There'll be others.
So, what happened?
At the house?
Well, my foster father
caught my little brother
wearing one of his ex-wife's dresses.
Started beating the crap out of him.
Seriously? He hit him?
Yeah. I mean, he used
to hit me all the time,
but, you know, whatever.
But, when I saw him going after Jude...
I just... well, I tried to stop him,
but he kicked me in the stomach.
So, I went outside, grabbed a baseball bat,
beat the hell out of his precious Trans Am.
The cops came. He told
them that I went crazy,
and he was defending himself.
Nobody seemed to care much
about my side of the story.
Hey sweetheart.
You ok?
I just... I don't feel
so good. My stomach hurts.
I don't think I'm going to be able
to go to Brandon's thing tonight.
What, you feel like
you're going to throw up?
No, I just... I think
I just ate something bad.
I really need to lie down.
Ok. Well, yeah, go lie down and
we'll see how you feel later.
Hey, so, what's going on with Mariana?
- What do you mean?
- Um, why is she pretending to be sick?
I don't know. Maybe she's actually sick?
Or it could be that time of the...
If you say "time of the month,"
I'm going to sign you up for a
women's health workshop at my OB-GYN.
Don't ever say that in
a house full of women.
Ok, ok. Jeez, well, if it's not that
than I don't know what to tell you.
- Ok.
- I'm home!
Hey, put that away. You need
to get changed for Brandon's...
- I just came down here!
- I know.
Go. Now, Jesus. Go!
Where is everybody?
- Hi!
- Hey.
What's wrong? Everything
all right with Callie?
No, I haven't even checked
on her yet. I just walked in.
I just... something's up with the twins.
- Meaning?
- Well, Mariana's pretending to be sick.
- Uh-huh, stomach ache? -
And Jesus is all clammed up.
He's not saying something.
Oh.
Do you think it's about
Ana? Do you think...
maybe I'm putting too
much pressure on Mariana?
Absolutely not. I think she
has just changed her mind.
They're not ready yet. Really, it's ok.
You keep me sane.
I don't know how...
sane you're going to feel after you
hear what happened at work today.
Now that Vasquez is leaving,
you're never going to guess
who Roberts is partnering me up with.
- Who?
- Mike.
Apparently, he asked for me.
Oh please, do not go all non-verbal on me.
- It is not a big deal, honey.
- Hmm.
- It's really not. It's...
- Mm.
Now who's all clammed up.
Come on, honey. It's Mike.
- It's just Mike.
- Hey Mike.
- Hey.
You guys ready?
Brandon, your dad's here!
It's time for your competition!
He'll be down in a second.
I think he's nervous.
Brandon?
So, I hear you and Stef are going
to be back on the beat together.
Oh, yeah.
Stef says you asked for her.
I did. Look, it was either me or a rookie.
I was never comfortable when she
was working with Vasquez, I...
Look, I just feel better
knowing I'm around. Ok?
And we got the kids to think about.
- Ok.
- Thanks.
- Mm-hm.
I mean, as a feminist, I'm totally
offended and everything, but...
as her wife, you know, thanks.
Yeah, just don't tell Stef I said that.
God, where's that kid?
Brandon, shake a leg! We're
going to do this thing!
Hey Mike, you clean up nicely.
Stef.
Hey, why aren't you changed?
- Hey, he's not here.
- What?
Yeah, they didn't walk home with us.
I just thought he was showing her around.
Her who? Her, Callie, her?
Yeah.
That's not like him.
He knows he has the music thing tonight.
- I know it's not.
- I don't know who this girl is,
or why you guys feel like you have to take
in strays like some damn homeless shelter.
- Ok.
- So, where the hell are they?
He's not answering. I'm going to try Talya.
Look, I'm sure he's fine.
He probably thought we were
going to meet him at the contest.
Why don't I just head over
there and check it out?
- Hey, have you seen Brandon?
- Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I had this app installed
on all of our phones
because that one kept losing his.
Ok.
She says the last time she saw him,
he was talking to Callie
after seventh period.
Maybe he's right. Maybe
we're just overreacting.
If we're overreacting, what
are they doing in San Ysidro?
What?
- Are they going to Tijuana?
- I'm going to kill him.
This is exactly what I was worried about.
- Let's go.
- I'll drive.
Hey, Brandon and Callie are missing.
What do you mean "missing?"
They never came home from school.
Oh, huh.
Hey, you didn't take
any of my pills, did you?
What? No. Why?
Well, Mom just got me a new
bottle, and now they're almost gone.
What are you looking at me for?
- I was just asking.
- Well, ask Brandon or Callie.
Excuse me, I've got to go.
Is that how you got all that money?
- You selling my pills?
- No.
'Cause I know sure as hell you
didn't get all that money from Mom.
Or maybe you did? Maybe we should ask her.
Why? Why would you do something so stupid?
You could go to jail for that.
What do you need all that money for anyway?
I've been talking to Ana.
Ana?
Our... birth mom?
She got back in town last
month. I found her online.
You said you didn't want to meet her.
No, I just...
I didn't want Stef and Lena sticking
their noses all up in my business, ok?
They wouldn't get it.
Ana needs some money...
You're giving her money? For what? Why?
- See, I knew you wouldn't understand.
- Understand?
You want me to understand
that this woman is not our mom?
She left her two kids so she
can run off with a dumb ass
and screw who ever she wanted.
She abandoned us. She left us.
Well, she came back.
I thought you were supposed
to be the smart one.
Jude.
Hello? Is anybody home? I need help.
Hang on!
Are you deaf or what?
- Can I help you?
- Uh, yes sir.
I, um, I was looking for the Metro.
- The Metro's a few miles from here.
- I got kind of lost.
- You're lost.
- Yeah.
All right, man.  You got to
go about six blocks that way...
Whoa, hey! What the
hell are you doing here?
- I just want to talk to Jude.
- No! Shut up! No!
- No, you get out of this house!
- One second...
- Hey, shut up!
- Ok, look. I am sorry about your car...
- No, get out of here!
- Hey, don't touch her!
- I can pay for it!
- Calm down, man.
- Ok, shut up.
- Ok, ok, ok...
Gun!
- Call 911.
- Lena, stay here.
You know what, buddy? Just shut up!
Police, freeze! Freeze!
Get down on your knees now!
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Get down on your knees now!
Put the gun down! Put the gun down!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
- Honey, are you ok?
- Hands on your head!
- Don't move!
- Man, this is my house.
Shut up! Shut up!
And who is that?
That's her brother, Jude.
Look, I was just trying
to do the right thing, ok.
I'm sorry about the scholarship.
- I know we could've used the it...
- Brandon.
I don't care about the
scholarship. That guy had a gun.
Yeah.
Get in there.
Hey, Skippy.
My brother used to have that backpack.
Cool.
I would really like you to understand
how this, tonight, could've
ended very, very badly.
Look, if you want to send me back to juvie,
then you just promise me
Jude will be somewhere safe.
You're not disposable, Callie.
You're...
you're not worthless.
Come on here, let's go, let's go.
We'll take them home
for now, Bill. It's fine.
It's fine. I will call you tomorrow.
Ok.
Hey.
You know I'm going to kill you,
if your mom doesn't kill you first.
Yeah.
I love you, B.
I love you, too.
I'm sorry.
But you didn't have to come.
Yes, I did.
Mariana?
Hey...
Wow.
You're so pretty.
Thanks. So are you.
How've you been?
Good. Good... back in town.
And, uh, you know, I'm just
trying to get back on my feet.
So, you got anything for me?
Oh, uh...
Here, I hope this helps.
Trust me...
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Don't worry about it.
So, you probably have
to get back home, huh?
Folks probably wondering where you are.
- My moms.
- What?
My moms will be wondering where I am.
Ok.
Thanks again.
I'm going to make sure this
guy has a terrible night.
Yeah, feel free.
And, I'll get a ride back later.
- All right.
- I'll... I'll see you at work tomorrow.
I talked to Bill.
He's going to make arrangements
to pick up the kids tomorrow.
No, no, no. No.
- What does that mean?
- That means that we are not sending these kids
back into that system right now.
All right? Not yet.
Are you sure? We really
don't have the room.
Then we'll make room.
Ok, we'll make room.
Buckle up!
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com