Previously on The Fosters...
She got into a fight
with her foster father?
That's how she landed in juvie.
This is for a few weeks, right?
You're stealing my pills?
What do you need all that money for anyway?
- I've been talking to Ana.
- Our birth mom?
You know, I'm just trying
to get back on my feet.
Here.
- Where are you going?
- It's my brother.
You're gonna get me sent back to juvie.
And Jude is gonna be stuck in that house.
Can I help you?
- I was looking for the metro.
- The Metro's a few miles from here.
Whoa, hey! What the
hell are you doing here?
- I just want to talk to Jude.
- No! Shut up! No!
Freeze! Get down on your knees now!
Hands on your head!
We are not sending these
kids back into the system.
- We really don't have the room.
- Then we'll make room.
Jesus, the trash needs to go out.
I shouldn't have to remind you.
- I took them out yesterday.
- Well, it's full again.
And get off your skateboard, please.
And, it's not because what you
did last night wasn't really dumb.
And I don't use those words
for lack of bigger ones.
It was really dumb.
My God, what were you thinking?
Running off, chasing
after some girl. Come one.
Even if it was to help her brother.
- Why didn't you just call me?
- I know, I know..
It was a big mistake.
It could have been a fatal mistake,
love, you had no idea
what you were walking into.
Could have been much much worse than that.
I mean, it won't happen again.
You're damn right it won't happen again.
I gotta be honest with you, my friend.
I was ready to drop the hammer.
But after talking with Lena, we have
decided that you are probably very aware
- of the potential consequences of your actions, yes?
- Yes.
And this is pretty out
of character for you,
so we are not going to ground
you, but I am telling you,
this will never ever happen again.
Hmm, where's Mariana?
Oh, she's still in the bathroom.
Mariana, come on! Let's go, babe.
We've gotta eat.
- Callie, can you put juice out for everybody?
- Yeah.
I didn't have time to do my hair.
Well, it's too late now sweetie.
We still have 15 minutes.
No no no. You guys have to walk
to school today. We have a thing.
Come on. Come eat.
I am not going to school
with my hair like this.
Well then you're not
going anywhere, ever again.
Stef, your pancakes are burning.
Great. I get to spend all
day looking like a ***.
***
- Enough.
- Ok, guys you have to be out the door in 10.
Stef and I have a meeting with Bill.
And then I'm gonna take Jude to come
later to school, to show him around.
He'll be ok. I promise.
I'm not gonna let them
split you two up again, ok?
Yeah.
All right, pancakes everybody.
Who wants pancakes? ***, you want pancakes?
Brandon, pass them around, please.
Ow! Ok, Jesus, how many times have we said,
no skateboard in the house?
- Have you taken your pill this morning?
- Yes.
- No.
- Jude, dude, come on.
- Sorry.
Some fruit, you guys.
Let's do this!
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com
What are you doing?
I didn't have time to
dry my hair this morning.
There were like 300 people in the bathroom.
You look fine, I'm sure
no one's going to notice.
What happened to your hair?
Jesus, you idiot!
He may be an idiot, but
damn your brother's so hot.
Oh my God, ew.
Hey, do you have any more you know what?
- I only have a couple left.
- No, and I can't get any more.
- Really?
- Really.
Ok, see you babes at lunch.
Bye. So, what happened last
night with your birth mom?
- Jesus found out.
- He found out?
- Did he freak?
- Completely.
- Did he go with you?
- No. He yelled at me.
So, how was it?
Honestly? It kind of sucked.
Well, at least you don't have to
invite her to your quinceanera.
That would've been awkward.
Come on, we're going to be late.
Have you thought any more
about what you want to do?
- About Callie and Jude?
- Mm.
No.
To be honest, I just keep thinking about
seeing you and Brandon in
that house with a gun...
- We were fine.
- I know you were fine.
I know that. But in my
mind, when you go to work,
you are writing parking tickets
and pulling cats out of trees.
- That's firemen.
- You know what I'm saying.
- Don't insult me.
- You know what I mean.
I just keep flashing back
to you storming into that house
with your gun pulled out...
It's what I do, love.
I get this awful feeling in my stomach.
And I cannot help but
connect that back to Callie.
- Meaning?
- Meaning,
I know that you said we're not
going to put them back in the system
but, I have some really serious concerns.
- That's Bill.
- There's Bill.
Ok, bye.
- Hey.
- Hey, you...
Ah, did I just see Callie down the hall?
I don't know, did you?
I'm just surprised is all.
I mean, I figured after
last night they would've...
- Would've?
- Sent her back to juvie,
or another foster home or something.
Yeah, well, they're not.
I mean, not now, at least.
Mm. Good.
- You ok?
- Totally. I'm fine.
- You're sure?
- Brandon, I'm fine.
Are we still on for Friday?
It's not every weekend
my parents go out of town.
- You know I'm down.
- Good.
Now get to class.
Then a few years later, when
Callie was 10, I think...
yes, that's right.
Her mother died suddenly.
Her father obviously wasn't in the picture,
and there were no other
family members to call on.
So, they were put into the system.
Unfortunately, they haven't
been able to land anywhere,
for more than six months at a time.
Could I trouble you for
some more coffee, please?
Yeah, of course.
Now, we keep trying to put
them somewhere permanent,
but then something happens,
and we have to move
them onto somewhere new.
Something happens? What
exactly does that mean?
- Something like last night?
- I feel terrible about that.
That is my fault.
I had an emergency on another case.
Otherwise, I would've been there for Callie
and connected her with Jude,
and none of that would've
happened. Thank you.
Look, they're really great kids,
they've just had bad luck.
That's just so heartbreaking.
So you are looking for
something permanent for them?
Always.
We already have three teenagers.
What do you think?
So, the seventh grade classes
are mostly on the south corridor.
With all the high school kids?
- Yeah.
- Does that mean I get to see Callie?
Well, not all the time,
but she'll be around.
And if you need anything
at all, I'm always here, ok?
- Hey.
- Morning.
- Everything all right?
- Um.
Hey Jude, why don't you
wait out in the hall,
and I'll take you to class in a sec.
Hey.
What's up?
So, I was on my way to class
and I found this lying by a trash can.
Pills.
Well, you know what this means.
Locker search. Everyone line up.
- What's this?
- It's ibuprofen. Over the counter.
For cramps.
Uh, you're good.
How many kids are you selling to anyway?
I don't know, five or six?
You better hope none of them are
keeping their stash in their lockers.
- Got the report filed.
- Good boy.
- You driving?
- I'm driving.
Ok.
- So, that was quite a night?
- Yes, it was.
Anybody run away this morning?
That's funny. No. Nope.
Gave Brandon quite a talking to though.
But I've decided not to
ground him, so he's thrilled.
What? You're kidding, right?
No.
The kid basically went awol last night,
damn near got himself killed.
Yeah, exactly. So, Lena thought that
he's very well aware
of the consequences and
no benefit to punishing him.
- Oh, Lena thought.
- Ok, take it easy. Easy.
First time he's ever done
anything like this before.
Right, which is all the more
reason to set boundaries.
We set plenty of boundaries for him.
Well, apparently not enough.
God.
Look, I'm sure hippie-dippie Lena with her
PhD in child... whatever the hell it is,
has some opinions about why punishing him
would damage his blossoming sense of self,
but the thing is, Stef, I'm his dad.
Yes, Mike. I'm well aware of that.
Right, and you should've
talked to me about it first.
Come on, it'll be fun.
I told you nobody'd go.
I thought we had a good time.
Well, I don't know what to tell you.
Tell me that you'll go out with me again.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Why do you have to be
such a bitch? Come on.
Hey, she said no, man.
- Yeah, I heard her.
- So, why are you still in her face? Take a walk.
Why don't you just relax, ok?
Why don't you get out of here?
- Watch yourself, crackhead.
- What'd you call me?
- Jesus, knock it off...
- Hey! What is going on here?
Huh?
Need the bathroom, Jude? Go ahead.
Are you ok?
- Mm-hm.
- Finding everything?
Yeah.
Ok, good. I just wanted to make sure.
Did you see Bill?
Yep.
Did he say anything?
Like what?
I don't know. Like anything?
He said, "hi."
- Why?
- Just wondering.
Now get back in there. Learn something.
This is not like you to get into a fight.
I know, I'm sorry. The
guy was being rude to Lexi.
Ok. So, you can't have a
conversation about that?
- Why did this have to get physical?
- I don't know.
Did you take your pill today?
Yeah.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. A hundred percent.
Ok, maybe it's time we called Dr.
Hitchin's and set another appointment.
I don't need to see... can't
I have a bad day once in awhile
without being some psych case?
All right. Don't let this happen again.
If you feel yourself getting worked up,
just take a deep breath and walk away.
Ok? Go to class.
Hey, you got in a fight? Lexi told me.
I didn't take my meds,
so I was kind of jumpy.
Why aren't you taking your pills?
I'm skipping a few days to save your ass
so mom wouldn't notice
the pills are missing.
Don't worry, they didn't
find anything in the lockers,
- so you're fine.
- Hey, calm down.
- You're gonna get us both busted.
- Us or you?
You're welcome, by the way.
- Hey.
I was just avoiding the whole
"who do I sit with at lunch" thing.
Gotcha.
- I'll let you practice.
- No, no. You can stay.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
So, you're really not
getting grounded or anything?
Are your moms usually that cool
or is it just 'cause you
never do anything wrong?
No, I mean, I do stuff.
It's not like I've never
got in trouble before.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Like?
- Like, I...
- I got caught stealing.
- Yeah?
- Yes.
- What?
A car. Yeah.
A matchbox when I was five.
Yeah. No, you're bad news.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Hm.
What?
Nothing. No, I just...
I wonder how...
you even know who you are if you just do
what everybody else thinks you should do?
Nice, do you play?
Uh, a little. I used to.
My mom taught me some before she...
Before she?
Lena, honey?
- Hi.
- Hey.
Listen, I'm sorry. Mike is right behind me.
- Why is Mike coming over?
- Because he thinks we should
have a discussion, a conversation
perhaps, in regards to Brandon.
- Hey.
Mike and I, we were talking at work and...
he feels that perhaps,
we've gone a little too easy on Brandon,
and that he may indeed need
some sort of punishment.
Ok, I hear that.
But unfortunately, we
already spoke to Brandon.
We can speak to him again.
Mike, I think that
Brandon really understands
the consequences of his
actions and there's no value...
With all due respect, what you
think isn't really my concern...
Hey, wait a minute, Mike.
Lena is his parent, too.
Respectfully, that may be true.
But I am his father and you're his mother.
Excuse me?
- You know what I mean.
- I know what you mean.
What do you think?
Lena, you know that I think
you are his mother, too.
No, that's fine. That's fine.
I'm not his mother, I'm not his father.
- Mike is right.
- No, he is not.
What do you think about
Brandon's punishment?
I think that Mike has a point.
- Hey bud.
- What's up?
What are we talking about?
We're having a discussion right now.
The three of us, if you don't mind.
Actually, we're talking
about your punishment.
But I thought I wasn't punished.
You are. You're grounded, one
week. School and home, that's it.
- What? No, but I made plans.
- Oh, you made plans.
- Yeah.
- Oh, that's funny,
'cause you didn't have
any trouble blowing off
your plans to be at the
music competition, did you?
Ok, and since when do you even care?
- Excuse me?
- Brandon?
Where have you been?
No, no, seriously, dad.
When do you even care? You're never around.
When have you ever cared? You call me once,
like every two days,
five minute phone calls.
Why should I even listen to you?
Great. This is awesome.
Let me know who I'm supposed
to be taking orders from.
That went well.
Honey, listen, that's...
not supposed to be the way...
- I'm listening to that.
- You can't skip your pills.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Thanks to someone I seem
to be missing a whole bunch.
- You got a better idea?
- You still have a few left, right?
How many? Like a week or so?
- Like, three.
- Ok, how about this...
you keep taking them and you
take them till you run out,
and we can tell moms you
dropped the rest down the sink.
Yeah, ok. Fine.
In case I haven't said it...
You haven't.
Well, I'm sorry. For all of this.
It's cool.
Sixteen.
And this one?
No, you know that. What do you have to do?
You have to divide it by the "y."
It's four. The answer's four.
You should've known that.
I did know that.
- No, you didn't.
- Yeah, I did.
- Uh-uh.
- Yeah!
So cheeky!
- Stop it!
- No, you stop it.
How long are we going to be here?
I don't know, kid.
- Finish your homework.
- Ok.
I am sorry I ambushed you, Lena. All right?
This was something that Mike felt
very strongly about, obviously.
When you feel like talking
to me, Lena. Let me know.
I thought we were on the same
page. I thought we agreed.
I've never felt like such a
stepmother in my entire life.
- Lena...
- And just so we're clear,
I am done disciplining Brandon if
this is the way it's going to be.
I'm just going to be
good-time stepmom from now on.
You want some candy,
Brandon? Sure, help yourself!
Want some cigarettes? Smoke
it up! Lung cancer be damned!
Want some booze? No? How about some heroin?
Oh, wow. Point taken.
Please put down the knife.
You're scaring me. Lena, come on,
love. What was I supposed to do?
Mike is Brandon's father.
This was a big decision
and we didn't include him in it.
Can you imagine how you would
feel if something like this
- happened with Mariana or Jesus?
- It's not the same thing.
- Mike is not the twins father.
- Obviously.
You know that's not what I
meant. You would not like it...
- If parental decisions were being made without me...
- Without you.
Yes, I get that, but in
what world is it ok for you
to take Mike's side in front of me?
I didn't take his side,
Lena. I simply said...
You humiliated me in front of him.
I'm sorry, that is not what I meant to do.
But you asked, what was I supposed to say?
You lie, Stef. You lie.
Ok, I'm sorry.
It's not easy for me either, you know.
It's no fun playing
peacekeeper between you and Mike
when you're acting like Israel
and Palestine. It kind of stinks.
Look, Brandon has three parents, period.
No getting around it. Mike
had no right to say otherwise.
I know that's not what
he thinks, I really do.
And we're all just trying to do our best to
figure this out.
I'm going to go talk to Brandon.
All right?
- We're ok for now?
- We're good.
Great.
- B?
- Yeah?
I get that you're frustrated,
it seems to be a common theme
around the house these days.
But, that's no reason to
talk to your father that way.
He's a good man, he's a good dad,
and he does care very,
very much, he always has.
I know, I know. I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
- I'm sorry.
I didn't mean any of it.
- It's just...
- I know.
You know what you need to do.
By the way, Lena wants you to know,
that if you ever need any
heroin, she's happy to help.
Huh?
Never mind, that was funnier
in my head. I'm sorry.
Oh, you playing again?
I remember the day you bought that.
Saved up all your money, all on
your own, I was so proud of you.
Call your dad.
Yeah.
Hi. Dinner is not quite ready yet.
Do you want something to drink or... ?
Is everything ok?
Yeah, I was just wondering
if you had any chores for me.
Chores?
Yeah, well, foster families are
gonna send us away right away,
they usually give us chores and stuff.
You know what?
You could really help me...
I forgot the salad forks.
So, are you and Stef married?
Well, not exactly. Not legally, no.
We're married in our hearts, I guess.
That's basically the same thing, right?
Basically, yeah.
Yeah.
Everyone, grab a seat.
So, we have something
to talk about, obviously.
Uh, Stef and I had our meeting with bill,
and we've come to a decision.
We are not in a position to offer
Jude and Callie a home forever.
But we would like you guys
to be as comfortable and safe
as possible, until bill does
find you a permanent home.
- However long that may take.
- It could be a week, it could be a year.
- We just don't know.
- Yeah.
We want this to be your
very last way station
ever, ever, ever. Ok?
So, that means, we need to get
you guys out of the living room.
I think you'll be ok to camp
down there one more night,
but tomorrow we're having
some beds delivered,
so after school let's help
get them settled in, ok?
Yes, Brandon and Jesus, could
use a little muscle, all right?
Jude, my sweet, new, young friend.
You'll be moving in with Jesus.
And Callie, you'll be moving
into Mariana's room, all right?
Hey Mariana! Lexi is here!
Hey.
Oh, hey.
I just wanted to say thanks.
I know you were just
trying to stick up for me.
I... I didn't mean to yell at you.
You didn't have to go
all Iron Man on his ass,
but, you know, thank you.
What are you doing? Come
on, I need your help.
I have to get rid of a bunch of stuff
so Callie can move into my
room. It's a freaking nightmare.
Seriously, I don't understand why
they just can't move into the dining room?
It's not like we ever use it, right?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Maybe we can put them in the closet
or under the stairs, like in Harry Potter?
I mean, come on guys. Let's
think about how they must feel.
They're not here forever. Let's try to
make them feel a little more welcome.
Easy for you to say. You're
not giving up anything.
Lexi, come here.
Wait, what do you mean? I thought
you weren't getting grounded?
What about Callie? If you're getting
punished, is she going back to juvie?
No. No, she's actually going to
be living with us for a while now.
Wait... you're not jealous, are you?
Of Callie? No.
Ok. 'Cause you have no reason to be.
Yeah, obviously. You know,
that's cool of your moms.
Letting her stay.
She was just trying to help
save her brother, right?
Yeah.
Brandon called you, right?
- Yeah, said he was sorry.
- Good.
He was kind of right, though.
No, he was not. He was
not right to talk to you...
Not about the me not caring part.
I mean, look, when was the
last time that you and Lena
really talked to me about Brandon?
Ok, listen, Mike. You're right. We have...
No, no, no. I'm not blaming you.
I'm not saying it's your
fault. That's not what I mean.
You guys are so good and
involved and there all the time.
I just feel like it was so
easy to turn the reins over.
I don't want to do that any more, Stef.
I don't want to hand my kid over.
I don't want to be some
half-assed version of a dad.
You're not a half-assed version of a dad.
I know, but you know what I mean.
You guys know she just
got out of juvie, right?
Kelsey, I told you not to tell anyone.
I know, but I think that they should know.
Watch out, she'll totally
shiv you or something.
- Shank.
- Huh?
A shiv is a thing, a
shank's what you do with it.
- Oh.
- My mom's a cop.
Damn girl, it's like Grand
Theft Auto around your place.
Seriously.
Hey Callie! Over here.
So, how are you?
I mean, I know it's been a
crazy couple of days for you.
Uh, no, I'm fine. Thanks.
So, where are you from?
Just around.
Uh-huh. Great.
Is that your brother you
were talking to this morning?
Yeah, that's Jude.
Wow, he's totally adorable.
Ah, he's all right.
- I like your bracelets.
- Thank you.
I should get some like that. So cool.
Yeah, I really like your scarf.
So, how long are you
guys gonna be here for?
A couple weeks, a month... six months?
I have no idea.
It's not really up to me.
Right... 'cause we should
get you in some clubs.
You know, so you can meet more people.
It's got to be hella boring hanging
out with Brandon all the time.
You'd know a lot about that.
Right? We're together
pretty much all the time.
Stef and Lena are so
supportive of our relationship.
Stef even buys his condoms.
Hello! How great is that?
Oh, it's really great.
So...
I just...
Yes.
So, I wasn't really right
in the head yesterday.
Meaning...
Meaning, um, I probably shouldn't have...
It's cool. But you probably shouldn't
go kissing me every
time you have a bad day.
Oh yeah? Who said you're the
only girl I kissed yesterday?
Oh, really?
Really.
You got a little...
What is it and who gave it to you?
You can tell me or we can call
the police and you can tell them.
It's up to you.
What's it gonna be, Kelsey?
Where'd you get the drugs?
Where is she?
This one kid, Connor,
was pretty nice, though.
They're reading this book,
a Wrinkle in... something.
- Time?
- Huh?
- A Wrinkle in Time.
- Oh yeah, that's it.
Anyways, I don't get it.
It's kind of confusing.
What?
Why are both my moms home?
What's going on?
Mariana, could you take
Jude upstairs, please?
We need to talk to Callie.
Yeah, sweets, it's ok. She'll be right up.
Callie?
We've been told that
you... stole Jesus's pills?
And have been selling them
at school? Is this true?
Is this true?
- No.
- You sure about that?
Uh-huh.
Then why would this
student say that you did?
I guess I'm just an easy target.
Right.
Will you give us a minute, please?
So, what do we do?
I don't know, maybe we should call Mike.
- Oh, yes, feisty.
- Uh-huh.
- I'm trying, love.
- I know.
- Mike didn't mean what he said about...
- I know, I know.
Mike called me, we talked.
Really, what'd he say?
That's between me and Mike.
So, did you ask Talya to
have lunch with Callie?
Wait, what? They had lunch?
- Talya has lost her mind.
- She's insecure, bro.
I mean, suddenly got this
hot 16 year old girl...
- You think Callie's hot?
- You don't?
I better figure something out,
or Talya's going to have
a complete meltdown on me.
Better do something big.
Make her feel special.
But I'm grounded, remember?
Improvise.
Hey, you didn't make
any plans tonight, right?
No, good, don't. I...
I'm gonna sneak out, and come see you.
No, I don't care if I get
in trouble. It's worth it.
Ok. Bye.
Where's Jude?
He's reading magazines in my room. He's ok.
Good.
I don't know what I'm gonna tell him.
So, what happened?
They think that I stole
your brother's pills.
- What did you tell them?
- Well, I didn't tell them that it was you,
if that's what you're asking me.
Why not?
As if they'd believe me.
Hey.
Are you really going to let
Callie take the fall for you?
They're gonna send her away.
They're gonna be so mad at me.
The other night,
when Ana just took all
that money from me...
like I was an ATM or something,
not even a person, much less her daughter.
I thought, "well, hey...
at least, I have two
moms at home who love me."
- They're gonna hate me.
- They're not gonna hate you.
- I promise.
- They're totally going to cancel my quinceanera.
Will you come with me to tell them?
Surprised you want to consort
with a known drug trafficker.
Well, did you do it?
What do you think?
I think you're playing the G chord wrong.
Try the six string on the third fret.
There you go.
Thank you... for the guitar.
You're welcome.
I can't remember anything.
I think that was a C there.
- I was right?
- Here.
And then, I think if
you move these two down,
you'll make another chord there.
Nice.
Hi.
It was me, I did it.
Did what?
The pills.
Ok.
You care to explain.
I was feeling like a freak.
Just tired being the kid with add.
Everyone always asking me,
"did you take your pill?"
"Did you take your pill?"
You know, so I stopped.
I started hiding them in my pocket.
Kelsey saw them at school
and she told me she heard
they make you really smart,
and really focused.
She needed some for a
paper she had to write.
So, I gave her one.
And some more.
And things just got out of hand.
G, C...
Hey Brandon,
will you excuse us for a sec?
Uh, yeah.
Um, well...
it would appear that we were given
some false information.
And I promise I'm going to find
out how that happened exactly.
Yeah, we're very sorry
that we didn't believe you.
We feel that trust is
something that has to be earned.
Right?
We would really like
to start earning yours.
- Yeah.
- Ok.
All right. Let's go.
I'm glad we're staying. I like it here.
Yeah?
Don't like it too much.
God, I can't remember anything.
Just keep trying.
I mean, it'll come back.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com