Previously on The Fosters...
After talking with Lena, we
are not going to ground you.
And you should have talked
to me about it first.
I... I don't wanna be some
half-ass version of a dad.
Brandon has three parents. Period.
Hey. Hey, hey. She said no, man.
So you were looking for
something permanent, for them?
And we want this to be your very
last way station ever, ever, ever.
What's it gonna be, Kelsey?
Where'd you get the drugs?
It was me. I did it.
Here.
Ok. Let's go. Time's up.
Mariana!
My turn.
- Girls take longer.
- No, no, no. But this isn't fair.
- Get out.
- Just gimme a second.
You're not supposed to be on the computer.
- If Moms find out they're gonna ream me.
- This sucks.
Yeah, well you shouldn't have been
giving away your freaking pills.
Come on. Let's go.
About time.
Yeah. It hasn't been like
15 extra minutes of anything.
So. thank you for that. What are you doing?
I gotta pee really bad.
What? Jude!
- I thought you were just...
- I'll be really fast! I promise!
If you wanna borrow something...
- Uh, no. It's ok.
- Ok.
I just thought you might be sick
of wearing the same three things...
I'm not gonna steal your earrings.
I mean, what am I gonna
do? Sell them at school?
Don't talk about things
you don't understand.
Ok. Well, what don't I understand, Mariana?
I mean you stole your brother's
pills, you sold them at school,
and then you let your
brother take the fall for you.
I never asked him to do that.
But you let him.
Buddy, can you do that in the
bathroom like everybody else, please?
- Come on.
- What's that?
We are brown baggin' I for a little while.
It's better for you. Go spit.
I don't eat cheese.
Since when? You had pizza
like two nights ago...
It's really bad for you.
Can I have tuna?
- If you want to make it.
- Mm.
All right, everyone.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where's Brandon?
Cold!
Oops. I guess there's no more hot water.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com
She spends like an extra 15 minutes
in the shower I'm not even kidding.
It's like my turn and they...
Sounds like you guys
need another bathroom...
Or four less kids.
I just want some privacy, really.
Yeah, well I don't think my parents
are going out of town again any time soon,
so I'm afraid you missed your
chance for privacy, mister.
Well, we can figure it out.
How? It's not like we'll be
alone at your place ever again.
Poor guy. How long is he in detention for?
- All week.
- Oof. That's rough.
What do you care?
I don't. I just feel sorry
for him. What's with you?
Nothing, I just...
look, I feel bad enough about it, ok?
Ok, but you really don't have to.
Think about all the times you
covered for him. He'll be fine.
It's not like he ever pays
attention in class anyway.
Look, Jude seems like a good kid...
He is.
But the Parent Board
is all over me on this.
Obviously, we're ok
giving you a little leeway,
but he has to pass the proficiency exam
that the other kids took to get in,
or I'm afraid you're going to
have to send him somewhere else...
I can't send him to another school.
He would be completely lost.
That's part of the reason
he's so behind right now.
Because he hasn't had
anybody to look out for him.
Look, I'm not unsympathetic, Lena...
The only sense of security this
kid has in the world is his sister.
Separating them would be terrible for him.
Look, I'm trying to protect you here, too.
You know how this works.
Our funding is based on performance.
And now I have a new seventh
grader who jumped the wait list,
who isn't operating at
even close to grade level.
Is it possible we could
just give him more time?
Before he has to take the exam, I mean?
I know if I just had a little while
to get him caught up I could...
Lena. He passes the exam on Friday,
or he's done at Anchor Beach.
Now, he's guilty, insofar
as he did commit the crime,
But he doesn't feel that way
until he actually gets caught.
Ok. I want everyone to write about
guilt in their journals this week.
Wait, write?
Like with a pen? Like longhand?
Yes, like longhand.
And don't worry. No one's gonna read it.
It's just for you to get in
the habit of writing every day.
Ok, guys. Seriously, I want you
to write about whatever it is
that you feel weird or
ashamed or guilty about.
You'll feel better about it, I promise.
Weak, Foster. Very weak.
And quit "nudging" me online.
- Hey, meet me tomorrow.
- Meet you? Why?
You're in detention all day, remember?
I'm gonna have Douglas
let me go to the bathroom.
So, two o'clock. I'll meet
you by the lifeguard stand.
I don't know. I have to think about it.
Foster!
What?
I'll see you tomorrow.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Talking to Lexi. What's the big deal?
No classes, no extra-curricular, no fun.
In school detention and home. Period.
But we've got a game this week.
Not my problem.
Jesus, you gave away your pills.
Do you not understand how serious that is?
This could have been a lot worse.
Use your legs, B. You're
not using your legs.
The twins are both mad because Moms
moved Callie and Jude into their room
and not mine, so like everyone's all...
everyone's all tense all the time.
That's more like it.
Nice. You want some water?
Yeah.
So, I was thinking,
maybe you might wanna spend
some more time at my place?
Maybe even move in with me.
Why?
Well, you know I mean,
the new kids in the house.
The place is busting at the seams...
I only get you the one night a week.
You're going be going off
to college before too long...
and I kinda feel like I'm missing out.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Could be fun. Why not?
Look, you don't have to say anything.
Just think about it and let me know.
You mind?
- What?
- The song. It's annoying.
You're in a good mood tonight...
I'm always in a good mood.
You're in a really good mood tonight.
Are you...
is there someone you haven't told me about?
What? No.
Really? Nothing's going on? Nothing at all?
Nothing between you and Lexi?
Not at all.
That's not what it looked
like this afternoon.
When? At volleyball?
We were just talking.
I was helping her with her kill.
With her kill, really?
What can I say, I'm irresistible...
Relax. You know I wouldn't date
one of your lame friends anyway.
Right?
So, I won't be able to go
to school with everyone else?
No, no, no. Honey, listen,
all we need to do is give you the test,
and once you pass it,
everything's gonna be fine.
If he passes it.
Well, yes, but all he needs a 65
or better, and we're good to go.
You can do that, right?
This isn't fair.
No, it's not. But this
is what I want to suggest,
Jude, you and I are going to
spend this week getting you ready,
and that way you will ace it for sure.
Deal?
Ok, remember to convert
to a fraction first.
- Good.
- Hey, B.
- Hey.
- How were the batting cages?
- Oh, uh, good, you know.
Yeah? What's up?
Uh, bud? I think we got
some good work done tonight.
So, why don't you run
upstairs and get ready for bed.
- Night, Bud.
- Night Jude, we'll be up in a minute.
What's up, babe?
Uh, um...
Uh, Dad kinda...
asked me to move in with him today.
Wow.
Well, he never mentioned anything to me.
And I really think that he
should have talked to me first.
Yeah. I guess.
Um. All right, well... don't
worry about it. I'll talk to him.
Yeah, ok...
I said, I'd think about it.
Well, there's really
nothing to think about.
I mean, it's not your choice.
It's not really your father's
either, for that matter.
What do you mean, I don't
get a choice? Why not?
Because you're, um...
- you're still a kid.
- I'm 16.
Yes, that's exactly my point.
You're 16, you're not an adult yet.
This is bull.
I'm sorry?
This is bull. I should get a say in this.
Well, you don't.
And we are done talking about this.
Oh, right. Ok, we're
done talking about this.
Yeah, 'cause that's, that's
your answer for everything.
Ok, let's just take a deep breath...
Right, B. Because you're a
prisoner being held captive
in this charming Craftsman in Mission Bay.
- Stef...
- What?
When did I ever get to choose anything?
Did I get to choose for you to divorce Dad?
Did I get to choose who
I was gonna live with?
You were five! Come on.
How about choosing if I have two
moms... did I get to choose that?
- That's enough, Brandon.
- Why?
Because I'm not doing exactly
what you want me to do?
No, because you're being disrespectful.
Oh, I'm being disrespectful?
How about you have a little
respect for someone else!
You need to stop talking right now.
Right, of course I do!
Because that's your answer.
Anytime anyone disagrees
with you, it's stop talking!
Be quiet! Do it my way!
You need to watch yourself, young man.
- Watch this, Mom.
- Brandon!
If you leave this house.
Stef. Stef! Let him go.
He needs to cool down.
And so do you...
Are you gonna be up much longer?
I can't sleep with the light on.
I'm not just some
selfish bitch, you know...
Ok.
I didn't sell the pills for me.
It's not like I bought
a new dress or something.
Then why'd you do it?
For my birth mom.
Did you hear me?
I'm listening.
Where were you?
I went to Aiden's.
You don't do that. You don't walk away.
I know, I know. I was just... I'm sorry.
I know. I'm sorry, too...
for raising my voice. But
that can't ever happen again.
You can get mad at me all you want to,
but you are not allowed to walk away.
It won't happen again. I promise.
Ok.
And, and... for the record,
I... I love having two moms.
That's good.
Um, you really made your point, Brandon.
I spoke with Lena and it's up
to you... where you want to live.
You can stay here, or you
can move in with your Dad.
It's your choice. Just let
us know what you decide.
Well, don't stay up too
long. 'Cause it's late, ok?
- Ok.
- All right, love.
You're back. That was some fight, man.
You heard that?
We all did. So what happened?
They're letting me decide.
Really? Wow.
I mean, moms are gonna
be devastated if you go.
And my Dad will be
devastated if I don't go.
You wanted to choose.
Good luck with that.
I just think, I mean, we're
gonna get a lot more time alone.
I just hope my moms don't get too upset.
Brandon they'll be fine.
Really. You can go visit
them, you know, whenever...
with all those kids in the house
I doubt they'll even notice.
Very good.
I thought you'd have a lot of guilt.
Good. Very nice.
Lose your pen? Ok.
Nice. Good.
Good.
I see some of us are still
wanting for inspiration.
Tell you what, why don't
you and Wyatt come see me
after school today and we can see
if we can get those juices flowing.
That's not what I meant.
You're incorrigible.
Look it up. Every single one of
you should know what that means.
Ok, turn to page 45.
So, we gonna talk about the
elephant in the car or what?
Not much to say. You wanted
Brandon to have a choice. He does.
You could've told him no.
I tried. It didn't go well.
Hey, can I have a breakfast
burrito, extra salsa, please?
- You got it.
- Thank you.
So what, you just gonna be mad at me?
I don't know, Mike.
Do I wish you had talked
to me about it first? Sure.
Would I have agreed to
let B decide? Probably not.
So, maybe this is for the best.
But I'll tell you what you blind-side
me with something like this again
I'm gonna bury you deep in the desert.
Fair enough.
Sucks being blind-sided, don't it?
So, all of this with
Brandon is just payback?
For what? Figuring out
I was gay and leaving?
It's a little late for payback, Stef.
I think so. Mike, come on.
If you're gonna rehash our
marriage for ten hours a day,
I'm going to ask Roberts for
another partner. Seriously.
Stef, it's not payback...
it's regret. It's me growin' up.
I got a kid who's going off on his own.
I'm just trying to do something right.
Hey.
So, Talya told me the news...
Huh?
You're moving in with your Dad?
Yeah.
Um, it's not...
this might be stupid, but it's
not because of me and Jude, is it?
No. No, no, not at all.
Just 'cause I mean, from what I can tell,
you seem pretty happy in the house.
- Yeah.
- Hot water not withstanding.
I am, I am. I mean, it's my house.
It's where I grew up.
So, why are you leaving?
Hey, shouldn't you be in class right now?
We are. Drama.
Leslie wanted to make sure the
posters went up today, so...
How'd you get out of ISS?
Oh, told Douglas that I had to take a leak.
I should probably get back.
- Listen...
- Yeah?
Thank you so much, for what you did.
Telling Moms all that.
You didn't have to do that.
It's cool.
I just wanted to let you
know how much I appreciate it.
You really are the best brother...
Foster! Foster. Hey!
So, what happened? Douglas wouldn't
even let you out to use the bathroom?
Well, then what? I was sitting
there for like half-an-hour.
I'm sorry 'bout that.
"Sorry 'bout that?"
- That's it?
- I don't...
I don't think this is a good idea.
Why not?
You know why...
'Cause of Mariana?
Do you honestly think
that she's gonna care?
I know she is. She told me.
Her brother and her best
friend like each other, so?
Most people would see that as a good thing.
Yeah, well, she doesn't.
We're just gonna do whatever Mariana wants?
Try using those to write with.
I don't think it's gonna happen, Timothy.
Maybe we're just not writers.
Have you ever heard of Joan Didion? No?
She's a writer. Tough lady. Kind of a pill.
She called writing, "a hostile act."
A way of "imposing your will on the world."
Now, I don't mean to point fingers, but...
two of the three people in
this room seem a little hostile.
To me, anyway.
The thing is, that sort of
writing takes real courage.
And you don't strike me as
someone who is afraid of much...
Come on. Come on. One line.
One thing that's been rattling
around in your head forever.
One thing you feel terrible about.
Get it out. Get it down on paper.
And see what happens.
- Hey, Bud.
- Hey. Ready.
Where we going? The Grill?
No, my place. I thought
I'd cook something tonight.
Seriously?
Yeah, seriously. It's not
like I never cooked before.
Unless it's pasta? B, I'd be very careful.
Seriously, he cooked me a
piece of fish once in 1997,
I can still taste it.
I'll have him back by nine.
I know.
I'm gonna get a snack.
Do you want anything?
Oh, hey don't do that.
Uh, we'll eat in front of the TV.
I finally got the surround sound hooked up.
Ok.
Oh and hey... you know, if you move in,
we could move that table out of the way,
and you could put your
keyboard and stuff there.
Yeah, yeah, that would be... that's cool.
Yeah, I mean, you know if...
- Right, yeah, of course.
- No pressure.
Yeah.
Hey what's... what's this?
Oh, that? You like it? I made it.
You made it?
Yeah.
That's the ship I was on
when I was in the Navy.
Yeah, I remember the name but...
you made this?
Good job, Dad.
Remember, this is half base times height.
I keep forgetting the formulas.
Maybe I'm just not smart enough.
Oh, honey. You are plenty smart.
And trust me, I know smart.
Considering you went to, what?
Six different schools
in the past four years,
you're doing really great...
Seven.
Seven different schools.
So, you still playing poker?
Uh, no.
How come? I mean I remember
you used to brag all the time
about milking those guys for beer money...
Ah, you know...
you do something for a
while, people get busy then...
I don't know. You just let it go.
Too bad.
It happens, kid..
I gotta get you home.
I mean, I can text Mom.
So, we can finish the movie.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Ok.
Hey, I got an idea. Let's play a game.
Why don't you run up and grab everybody
and get something out of the game closet?
Hey, Talya. Come on in.
Uh, Brandon's not here, though.
Tonight's the night he has
dinner with his Dad, remember?
Oh, shoot. I forgot.
That's ok. You're welcome to wait
if you want. He should be here soon.
And we're just about to play
a game, if you'd like to join.
- Yeah, sure.
- Ok.
Why don't you throw that
stuff in Brandon's room.
- Hey, Callie!
- Hey...
We're playing a game?
Yes, we are playing a game.
All of us?
Yes, all of us. We used to do
this all the time, remember?
We just got out of the habit,
and I think now that
Callie and Jude are here,
it would be fun to start
the tradition again.
I'm sorry, did somebody say, "Game?"
- Really?
- Mm-hm.
You better get ready to lose, lady.
She always loses.
- See? Fun.
- Fun! Fun for everyone.
They're so much fun. I'm really
gonna miss hanging out here.
You know, now that Brandon's
moving in with his Dad.
Um, have you talked to him lately?
'Cause I just don't think that's happening.
- A boomerang?
- A boomerang...
- Really, a boomerang?
- A weapon of some sort.
- Hey, bud.
- Hey.
We just started, We saved room for you.
You can be the top hat.
So...
I think I'm gonna move in with my Dad.
Ok. Cool.
All right. Um, before we get started,
uh, does anybody want anything?
I'm gonna get some tea.
Do you want anything?
Ok.
- Hey.
So, you're really leaving, huh?
Yeah.
Hey, uh, thanks for letting me use this.
What are you doing?
That wasn't a loaner.
Really?
Yeah, no. It's for you.
I don't know what to say.
You don't have to say anything.
Just make sure you play it.
So, I guess you decided you
need more hot water, huh?
Yeah.
- Well, thanks.
- Yeah. No worries.
So, I'm gonna move the bed to that wall.
Get like a couch in here or something.
Just, really make this
place a serious bachelor pad.
Settle down. This is still my room.
What am I gonna do without you here, man?
It's just gonna be me and a bunch of girls.
And Jude.
Yeah. And Jude.
You'll be fine. Just stay out of trouble.
Yes, you. Stop giving out all your pills
to every cute girl in
school, for one thing.
It wasn't me.
- What?
- It was Mariana.
You're joking, right?
She wanted to have some money
to give to our birth mom.
What the hell, man. What are you doing?
Why would she do that? And why
would you take the blame for her?
Mariana asked me to go with
her to tell Moms what she did.
She was just about to say something.
I looked over at her face,
just at her stupid, scared face.
It looked just like it did when we
moved into our first foster house.
And I couldn't let her do it.
I mean, everyone's always
mad at me all the time anyway.
So, I figured, what does it matter?
But at least it's over.
All of this being grounded,
and In-School Suspension...
it was totally worth it, now that she
knows what a loser our birth mom is.
I mean, you know some day you're gonna
have to let Mariana fend for herself.
I never touched it!
Why would you do that?
- Good luck with those two.
- It was moved!
No one else has even been in here!
- I never touched it!
- Hey! Enough shouting!
What is going on?
- She read my journal.
- No, I didn't.
Well, somebody did. I left it right here
second from the bottom and
when I came back, it was moved.
- Well, it wasn't me.
- Mariana, tell me the truth...
I am! I never touched it.
Ok, Callie is it possible that it wasn't
really moved? That you just think it was?
Why? Because Perfect Mariana
could never do anything wrong?
Yeah, maybe you should get to
know your daughter a bit better.
Wait, what does that mean?
You know what? Forget
it. Don't worry about it.
You're probably right.
It was probably my fault.
I just forgot or something, probably.
I can't live with her.
Well, you have to. So, figure it out.
Why'd you have to get so mad?
Why can't you just get along with her?
- She read my journal.
- What do you care?
- It's just a stupid journal.
- See for yourself.
You wrote about Liam?
He said he wants a hostile act...
Time's up, Jude. You all done?
I'll correct it, and I'll let you know.
I only need a 65 and I can stay, right?
Yes... listen to me.
Whatever happens, I'm
really proud of you, ok?
Go on, get to class.
I'll come find you later.
What's that noise?
Brandon.
Brandon?
Playing basketball? Oh, boy.
He hasn't done that since
he failed that final.
I think he's feeling guilty.
- About what? About leaving us?
- About leaving you.
Oh, please.
Go talk to him, Stef.
What am I supposed to say?
He wanted a choice, he got
a choice. He made a choice.
I'm doing the best I can...
That's not good enough.
- What do you mean?
- You don't get to do this.
- Do what?
- You don't get to have hurt feelings and pout.
- I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
You have to step up. You
have to go help your son.
You have to put away whatever
it is you might be feeling,
and be the better person.
'Cause that's what parents do.
Oh.
- Lucky.
- Oh, please.
I've been known to shoot a
basketball or two, my friend.
You and Dad were such
jocks. What happened to me?
Oh, come on. You got
the more important stuff.
You're funny and smart
and talented as hell.
And more than that, you're kind.
And you know who you are.
You know what makes you happy.
That's an amazing thing for someone
your age, B. Don't take that lightly.
Just do what makes you happy, B, ok?
You do that and I'll be fine, I
promise. That's the way it works.
You don't, have to take care
of me or your Dad or Lena.
It's the other way around.
I didn't read your journal.
I know you don't believe
me, and that's fine.
I mean, why should you?
I'm just the latest girl you've
been forced to share a room with.
I remember what that was like.
Being passed around all the time.
I don't think I ever felt
safe until I got here.
It took me a long time to trust anybody.
So, I get it.
But I didn't read your journal.
Yeah, comin'!
Hey. What's going on?
I thought we weren't
moving you in till tomorrow?
Um, yeah, um... about that.
You ok?
Yeah... I just. I, uh, I can't...
You can't what?
Move in with you.
Ok.
I just, I'm sorry.
It's ok!
I just, I can't leave
Mom... and everybody else.
Don't worry about it.
- You sure?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Look, listen... this was never
supposed to be a bad thing.
You do what you gotta do.
I'm gonna be all right.
I mean it.
Ok?
Is that a, uh...
is it a piano?
Oh yeah, yeah. I rented it.
But it's fine. You can
come play whenever you want.
I'm sorry.
Oh, about time.
Sorry my parents wouldn't let me come.
- Hurry up. We've been waiting forever.
- Ok, we were making popcorn.
Unless, of course, you don't want any?
I don't think they want any.
We'll just have this for us.
- I'll take some.
- Come on...
- All right, ask nicely.
- Pass that down.
Here we go, here we go...
- This is ours.
- Jude?
Pass it down, pass it down...
- What you working on?
- English homework.
I have to write a story,
and I need a name for the bad guy.
You know we busted this dealer.
Uh, his name... really bad
guy. His name was Freddy.
- That's a good name.
- What about Sanchez?
Like your boss? No, no, no.
Jude, you cannot use that.
Does it have to be a
boy? Or can it be a girl?
How about Liam?
Hear one you like?
Good. All right, Lena.
Back in your seat. Let's go.
No talking. Anybody.
Quiet. I've killed for less.
Talking during the movie.
- What about you?
- Hm?
All right, here we go. Movie is starting.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com