Previously on The Fosters...
So, how long are you
guys gonna be here for?
I have no idea. It's not really up to me.
You're not jealous, are you?
Of Callie? No.
I don't think this is a good idea.
'Cause of Mariana?
Do you honestly think
that she's gonna care?
I know she is. She told me.
So that's it? We're just gonna
do whatever mariana wants?
I want everyone to write
about guilt in their journals.
Don't worry. No one's gonna read it.
It's just for you to get in
the habit of writing every day.
- She read my journal!
- No, I didn't!
You wrote about Liam?
I have to write a story, and
I need a name for the bad guy.
How about Liam?
__
Whoa, leave yourself some
room to breathe, sweetheart.
- Come on, I don't need to breathe.
- Yes, you do.
Do you think the top is too...
- Busty?
- Boring?
Right?
- You should jewel it.
- Ah, si.
- Uh, does that cost more?
- Un poco.
- Por favor, mama?
Gosh, ok.
__
Como?
She's asking if your
father's tie is going to match
with your dress for the
father-daughter dance.
__
Ah, que bueno.
Uh, so you can dance with a padrino or...
a close friend de la familia.
She's dancing with her moms. Right?
Oh.
Hey! Sorry, I'm late!
Hi, sweetie.
So, oh my goodness, you
look beautiful, sweetheart!
Did you see her face
when Stef walked up in her uniform?
Hilarious.
I hate when people say "bueno,"
like you need their approval for something.
When you tell people that
you have a mom and dad,
they don't say, "How wonderful."
Who cares?
I wish I had two moms
throwing me a quinceanera.
My parents refuse and we're Latino.
I mean, so are you, but
you know what I mean.
Yeah, totally.
I just want this to be like, the party that
everybody talks about for
the whole rest of high school.
You know what you need...
- Three hundred dollars?
- Shh.
For a dress she's only going to wear once?
We'll cut it short and
she can wear it to prom.
We're spending a fortune on this party.
It's not just a party, and we
already set this money aside.
Yes, before we had two more mouths to feed.
Love, I'm just asking can
we just rein it in, please?
Did you talk to her about
the Kelsey situation?
- Yes, I did.
- And how did that go?
So, Lexi and I were talking...
can we get a bubble machine for the party?
- No.
- Sure.
- Yes.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com
Make them thinner than that, sweetheart...
I'm just making sure you
have Mariana's playlist...
- Good job, buddy.
- ... nothing too provocative or
with any explicit lyrics.
- What's for dinner?
- Not chips, my friend.
Hey, can Talya stay for dinner?
- Ooh, Lexi, too?
- Sure.
Hey Callie, how was your day?
Uh, it was good.
Uh, so Callie, you know my friend Kelsey?
Oh, the one who lied and
said I sold her drugs?
- Yeah, well she's in rehab.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
So, do you want to take
her place in my court?
I think that is a great idea, Mariana.
Um, what do you think, Callie?
- Uh, sure, I guess.
- Great.
We'll just have to hurry and get
your gown fitted before Saturday.
I have to wear a gown?
Well, you don't have to do anything.
- And we get to do a waltz.
- It's gonna be fun.
- Like eating glass.
- Hey, shut it.
So, who does Callie get to dance with?
Brandon.
Yeah, I mean, but... you're my date.
Well, duh.
- Hey, B? Hey.
- Yeah?
Everything ok with you and Talya?
- Yeah, why wouldn't it be?
- I don't know, just...
Brandon, listen.
You know that, I'm assuming
that you know that...
well, you know, foster
siblings are not allowed to...
Hook up? I don't know what
you guys call it these days?
There's nothing going
on between Callie and I.
- Callie and me.
- Yeah, ok.
It's just, when the twins
got here you were nine.
- Right, and now I'm a horny teenager.
- Yes.
Hm.
Mom, I have a girlfriend
and I know the rules.
- Ok.
Will you do me a favor and
take these to your brother?
Tell him to please stop leaving
his crap around the house.
- Crap is not a bad word.
- It's not a nice word.
Well, give me a word to say then.
How's your mom?
- She's fine.
- Yeah?
She's taking a shuttle
from the airport tomorrow.
Well, that's good. That'll help us, right?
Yeah, what would help us is
if she wasn't coming at all.
Oh, my gosh.
I'll never understand why
Dana stresses you out so much.
She's nothing but lovely to me.
You're not her daughter.
Speaking of daughters,
I think ours might be
feeling a little embarrassed.
About what?
About dancing with us at her party.
Did she say something to you?
- No.
- Well, stop projecting.
Mariana's always been
very proud of us, really.
She's fine.
Should I have Mariachi? That's traditional.
So is having a Catholic mass
and you're not doing that.
Yeah, true.
What about the shoe ceremony?
- Uh-uh. No.
- A doll thing?
My mom's going to be here any minute.
I'm going to go use the ladies' room.
The ladies' room?
Hey, so I know your moms
made you ask me to be in your party.
So, I can tell them I don't want to do it.
I don't know. Whatever.
If you don't want to.
No, it's not that I don't want to.
It's if you don't want me to.
I don't mind.
- You know, you don't have to.
- No, I know I don't have to.
Ok, well, it's up to you.
Ok. Well, then yeah. But
I don't know how to waltz.
Well, neither do I.
A friend of our moms is teaching us.
Cool.
- I'm in here.
- Hey!
- You didn't lock the door?
- I'm sorry.
I hate sneaking around like this.
- But, it's kind of hot.
- I mean it.
Fine, let's tell her now.
Not before her party.
After.
I shouldn't even be doing this.
- Yes, you should.
- I have to go home.
- No, you do not.
Go. Go before Mariana thinks I fell in.
- Hey.
I just wanted to say goodnight to you guys.
And Jude, thank you so much for helping
out with dinner, you did a great job.
Thanks.
- Night, Mom.
- Hey you, Jesus Foster.
You're being a real sport
about Mariana's party, eh?
You're a good brother. It's ok.
Just as long as I'm the one who
gets the car when we turn 16.
- Yeah, that's gonna happen.
- Yeah, what he said.
All right, goodnight you guys.
- Thanks for dinner.
- Yeah, of course.
- What?
- Nothing.
- Hey, where's Callie?
- Bathroom.
Oh, those look fantastic,
sweetheart. Good job.
All right, goodnight, lovely.
Mm. Don't stay up late, ok?
- Ok, goodnight, Mom.
- Oh...
Hey, listen, you know,
Mama said something to me,
and I just wanted to check in with you.
You're not embarrassed to dance
with us at your party, are you?
That's a sad lunch, but I
guess it beats prison food.
Really? That's your opening line?
I was going to ask about your rap sheet,
but I thought that was rude.
That's where you're supposed to laugh,
and you realize that we're
both outsiders who nobody gets.
And then you get my name
tattooed on your neck,
until it all goes terribly wrong,
and you have to turn it into a snake
just biting your earlobe.
What do you want from me?
What every guy wants.
Stimulating conversation.
And sex. That's probably
off the table, huh?
Look at that smile.
So, listen, some of us are
hanging out at the beach
by the pier, Saturday
night, you should come.
- I can't, I have a thing.
- What kind of thing.
The kind that you'd make
fun of if I told you.
When your thing gets boring...
you know where to find me.
Don't be shy. Place your right
hand on your partner's waist.
And slightly around to
the small of her back.
Extend the left hand.
Palm raised.
Callie, rest your hand gently in his.
Other hand, up on his shoulder like so.
A little closer.
Good, hold that position.
In partner dancing, connection is key.
So, Brandon and Callie,
look into each others eyes.
Breathe.
Connect. And you two.
And over here. Right hand, on her waist.
Left hand...
Everyone? Gram's here!
- Dana, you made it.
- Of course I made it.
- Good to see you.
- Oh, hello beautiful.
- Hi Mom.
- Oh, your skin looks good.
You've been moisturizing,
but my God, you're pale.
Baby, you need some sun.
Yeah, but she's gorgeous. Look at her.
Of course, she's gorgeous.
- Gram!
- And there's my beautiful birthday girl.
Oh, and my handsome birthday boy!
Your grandfather's very
sorry he couldn't be here,
but he got stuck in Paris at a conference.
I wish I was stuck in Paris.
You play your cards right
and I will take you one day.
Where's my other dashing grandson?
Uh, practice.
Well...
you must be Callie.
- And you must be Jude.
- Yes, ma'am.
- It's lovely to meet you both.
- Thanks.
Everyone in this house calls me Gram.
Guess what, I've got fabulous presents...
Gotta be out the door in 15!
- Wow.
- Wow yourself.
Mm, we should dress up
for each other more often.
- I know.
- Or you could check your email.
Oh, I'm sorry...
Everything's done, sweetheart. Let it go.
I just want her party to be perfect.
She's going to be the center of attention.
For Mariana, it don't
get no better than that.
Ok, you guys need another bathroom.
- You look lovely, Dana.
- You really do, Mom.
Thank you. It's a miracle
because no black woman
can tame the mane in 15 minutes.
Luckily, you don't have that problem.
Yeah, I don't exactly
just wake up like this.
- Baby, that is a compliment.
- Ok, gift bags. Enough.
It's good... it's good like that.
Well, my you look handsome.
Well, you too... pretty, I mean.
Oh, right, I think.
Help me with the gift bags.
Bring 'em out to the car.
Thanks.
- Uh, you need help?
- What?
Oh, uh... no. I got it.
You look... nice.
- Hey.
Look at you, hottie.
Um...
Well, I should take these to the car.
- You look pretty.
- You, too.
It really is nice for Mariana
to ask you to be in her court.
Seeing as how, you know,
this is a temporary situation.
Well, you never know. I mean,
they might decide to keep us.
Maybe.
- I mean, unless...
- What?
- They knew something.
- Something?
Like what happened with Liam.
You make it a habit of reading
other people's journals?
Just people I don't trust.
Going to go help Brandon.
What's going on?
Hey. You look nice.
Oh, thank you. So do you.
That Lena's one lucky lady, huh?
- Ok.
- So, listen...
- I wanted to give you this.
- Child support? That's great.
It's for Mariana. It's for the party.
Look, I know this is costing you
guys a fortune and I asked around.
It's tradition for friends and
family to help out with these things.
It's very sweet, Mike. I really do
appreciate it, but we can't accept this.
I'm not taking that.
If you don't take it, I'm
going to be deeply offended.
And you, of all people, should know
you don't want me deeply offended.
- Well, thank you very much.
- Ok.
Actually, Mike, there is
something that you could do for me.
Um, I know it's last minute,
but Mariana has actually asked
if you would do the
father-daughter dance with her.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Seriously, me?
Wow. Yeah, of course. I'd be honored.
- Ok.
- I mean, you ok with that?
Yeah, well, apparently
dancing with your two moms
is not exactly quince tradition, so...
just roll with the punches.
- What about Lena?
- Oh no, it's fine, really.
We want her to have the party she
wants and this is what she wants.
Ok, well, she's lucky to have you two.
- You're great moms.
- That hurt to say, didn't it.
No, not at all. Hey, look
at you in your penguin suit.
- Huh?
- Never mind.
If I'm going to cut a rug with Mariana,
I'm going to need a little liquid courage.
Ok.
Wait, Mariana is dancing with Mike?
I thought she was dancing with you two.
It's fine, Jesus. Will you please
finish up this table for me?
Thanks, love.
Ok.
You look like a princess.
I feel like I'm going to throw up.
What if it's no fun? What if
I trip and fall on my face?
You won't, and it's going to be amazing.
- What is that?
- Your birthday present.
I wanted you to open it first.
Help me open it.
Oh, my God. Did you do this all yourself?
- Where did you get this picture?
- Your moms.
- I loved that dress!
- She was new to our school
and she wore this princess
dress every day for like a month.
I was obsessed with Belle.
And one day she fell on the
playground and ripped it.
And I burst into tears.
Never mind the fact that
her knee was all bloody.
It was humiliating. Everybody
laughed at me, except for Lexi.
She helped me up and took
me to the nurse's office.
You were my first friend.
And best friend.
Thank you. I love you.
I love you.
Can I interrupt?
I'm going to go get everybody together.
I'll see you out there.
Me, too.
Honey, you look beautiful.
Thank you.
So, what's in the box?
Open it and see.
Oh, my God, it's gorgeous.
Every girl wears a tiara on her quinces.
Oh God, it looks so expensive.
It was, don't tell Mom.
Thank you.
Beautiful, beautiful.
- She's my best friend.
- So?
So, I'm not thinking about her
feelings, I'm being selfish.
What are you talking about right now?
You're not being selfish.
Mariana's the selfish one.
My mom's just spending a bunch
of money on this stupid party,
she's not even dancing with them.
You know what else? She's still
in contact with our birth mom.
After I saved her ass.
We're not ending this.
- Don't do this.
- I'm sorry.
Hi honey, did you find Lexi?
- No.
- You ok?
I'm fine.
- Hey, have you seen Lexi?
- No.
Sorry, I was in the bathroom.
You're going to the bathroom a lot lately.
Maybe you have a bladder infection.
Mariana?
Here sweetie, on your left wrist.
Ok, everybody, couple up.
The DJ's going to announce the court,
and then Mariana and Jesus,
you'll make your grand entrance.
You all look wonderful,
beautiful, handsome.
Good luck. Come on, Talya.
- Ready?
- All right.
- What are you doing?
- I think we should switch.
Sam's too tall for Lexi.
Works for me.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome
to Mariana's quinceanera!
Now, can I have everyone please rise
and give a warm welcome
as you receive her court.
Starting with Lexi Rivera and Sam Wilkins.
Let's keep it going with
Callie Jacob and Brandon Foster!
Relax, this is your big moment.
And now, the moment we've
all been waiting for,
ladies and gentlemen,
Mariana Foster and her
brother Jesus Foster.
But first we'd like to
kick things off with the
traditional padrino dance.
Please welcome family friend, Mike Foster.
- Is Mariana ok?
- She's fine.
Hey, what was that
about? Did I do something?
You need to tell your girlfriend to chill.
Why, what she'd do?
She thinks I have a thing for you.
What... she said that?
Can you just tell her that
she has nothing to worry about?
Please?
Very nice.
At this time, we'd like to welcome
Mariana's court to the dance floor for
the traditional Viennese Waltz.
All right, you're dancing with me. Come on.
- I know.
- Know what?
About you and Lexi.
Dance.
We didn't want to tell you.
We didn't want to ruin your party.
Well, you did.
Ok, forget what I said
about Talya. I'm sorry.
You have nothing to be sorry about.
I don't get why it's such a big deal.
This doesn't change anything.
You could have any girl you wanted.
Why'd it have to be my best friend?
Can we have everyone back
to the dance floor, please?
What do you say, Dana? You
want to get your groove on?
- Why not.
- Come on.
Oh, I don't know who should be more scared!
That's right.
- Oh no, do we have to?
- Yes.
- You guys are so great.
- Um, I'm thirsty.
- Mariana.
- I have nothing to say to you.
Mariana, wait.
Brandon.
Brandon? What is going on?
Don't play dumb with me.
Callie told me what you did.
Ok, I read her journal because...
Wait, wait. You read her journal?
- Yes, and I'm glad I did...
- I can't believe you.
No. Shut up! I can't do this anymore!
- I'm done.
- Please...
Fine, but ask her.
Ask her about Liam.
Mariana.
- Can we talk?
- Talk about what?
How my best friend and brother lied to me?
We didn't lie to you,
we just didn't tell you.
Same thing.
And you know what hurts the most?
Hearing all the awful things
that Jesus said about me.
And you didn't even defend me.
That's not what a best friend does.
Yeah, I'll have another double. Neat.
You got it.
Hey, two white wines, please.
Hope you're pacing yourself, Mike.
It's a party, Stef. Have some fun.
This is a lovely party.
Thanks.
I know money's been
tough for you and Stef...
- Mom, we're fine.
- I know you're fine,
but with two more mouths to feed,
this is a lot to spend on a birthday party.
Well, it's not just a birthday party.
This is about Mariana
embracing her cultural heritage.
About being part of the Latino community.
Which, of course, she isn't.
I'm just saying being that Latina isn't
just about the color of her skin.
- But being black is?
- What?
For you being black has always been about
the color of a person's skin.
- That's not true.
- Yes, it is.
All I've ever said is
that dark skinned people,
have a different experience
than light skinned ones.
And by different, you mean more authentic.
I mean harder.
Honey, dark skinned people
face more discrimination.
That is just a fact of life.
So, maybe we are trying to make up
for what we couldn't give Mariana.
But I understand how she feels.
Do you now?
You were raised by a black mother.
And by a white father.
And I never felt accepted
by either community, Mom.
Well, I'm so sorry if you had such a
tough time being a beautiful
light skinned woman...
- Oh, Mom...
- But like it or not,
the color of your skin
has afforded you more
opportunities than anyone
like me has ever had.
That is what you've always assumed.
That being biracial
has made my life easier.
Because it has.
Like it or not, you will
never know what it is like
to be a black woman in America.
Look at the bright side,
now we can dance together.
I don't really feel like dancing.
I should go home. Mariana
doesn't want me here.
No, I want you here. It's my birthday, too.
- How did she find out?
- I don't know.
But look, she's not
letting it ruin her party.
We shouldn't let it ruin ours.
What's that about?
They have a thing for each other.
How do you know?
I pay attention.
They're not going to keep us, you know.
What are you talking about?
Brandon.
Ok, Jude? I'm not stupid, ok?
But sometimes you do stupid things.
Excuse me. Do you want to dance?
Go.
Hey, I've been looking all over for you.
Is one of those for me?
Is one going to be enough?
There's not enough wine in this world.
This about your mom?
She just told me...
I don't know what it's
like to be a black woman.
She's not right, you know that.
She's right about one thing,
and that's why I wanted to
have this party for Mariana,
and why I don't give a
damn how much it costs,
because I understand what that's like.
Not knowing where you belong.
I felt like that my entire life.
You know where you belong.
I shouldn't be doing this.
- This is Mariana's party.
- Hey, hey, hey...
Listen to me.
This is her party but you
can cry if you want to.
I love you.
Can I have everyone's attention?
Can everyone please find their seat?
And can I have Stef and Lena
join us on the dance floor?
Mariana, your moms have something
they'd like to say to you.
Ok, first of all, Jesus, will
you please come join your sister?
Ok, first we want to thank
all of our friends and family
for coming to join us and celebrating this
very, very special
birthday today. Thank you.
Our babies are 15! Could you believe this?
To our beloved Jesus and Mariana,
you have brought so much
joy and love to your moms,
and to your brother Brandon's life as well.
He begged us and begged us
for a brother or a sister,
and got both in one fell swoop.
Um, we love you so very much,
and since a picture is
worth a thousand words,
I'm going to shut up and
we're going to watch this.
So, go over there.
Ok, and Jesus, just so you don't
think we forgot about you...
Happy birthday!
Not in the house, young man.
Thank you so much.
Now, may I please have the rest of
the family up here for a photo, please?
Come on.
Come on, Callie and Jude.
Callie, come on.
- All right, Fosters.
- Come on.
Everyone together now.
Closer...
All right.
Scooch in. Everyone scooch in.
- One, two, three.
- Look at that.
Smile!
Honey, it's a beautiful party.
Yay!
- What happened to Talya?
- She left.
- Are you ok?
- Nope.
I broke up with Talya.
- Because of me.
- No, no, I...
I mean, I'm sure that's what
she thinks, but it's not.
I broke up with her because
she's doing stupid things.
Like reading your journal.
- She told you.
- She didn't tell me what it said.
I didn't want to hear it.
Callie, I already know everything
I need to know about you.
Hey.
Callie? Hey.
Callie? Callie, wait.
Hey! Brandon?
You haven't said boo to
your old man all night.
- Sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
Come here, come here.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I love you so much. Look at you, hm?
You're a man, now. You're all grown up.
I wish...
What?
I wish I could do it all over again.
Dad.
Ok, I know it's a party, so go have fun.
I'm going to go home.
Ah, I think I should drive you home.
I think you're right.
I am a police officer,
and I have an example to set for
the fine people I protect and serve.
- I'm this way.
- All right.
Mariana? Some of your
guests are starting to leave.
What's the matter? Aren't
you having a good time?
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
For being selfish.
Honey, what are you talking about?
This party.
It cost so much and
you both worked so hard.
I didn't dance with you. I
should've danced with you.
I have the best moms in the world
and I should've danced with you.
- Baby.
- Honey, it's ok.
No, it's not.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You know what you need?
A mama sandwich!
- No!
- Yes! Mommy sandwich!
- We love you.
- I love you, too.
Lexi, I'm not letting you leave
here without dancing with me.
Did I say it was formal?
I just assumed.
You look dumb in that dress.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Do you want a beer?
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com