Previously on The Fosters...
My foster father caught my little brother
wearing one of his ex-wife's dresses.
Started beating the crap out of him.
Foster siblings are not allowed to...
- Hook up?
- There's nothing going on between Callie and I.
You look nice.
What do you want from me?
Stimulating conversation... and sex.
You could have any girl you wanted.
Why'd it have to be my best friend?
- You read her journal?
- Yes. Just listen to me...
I can't do this anymore! I'm done.
- She told you.
- She didn't tell me what it said.
I already know everything
I need to know about you.
Callie, wait.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
I meant to pick up some guacamole
from that place you love.
Oh, that stuff's so good, too.
Sorry, Mariana called, then Jude
needed me, and I just... forgot.
Remember when you used to love me?
Don't do that. I feel terrible.
I guess, just salsa will be fine...
Hey, where do you think
you're going, young man?
Can't we just go up and play video games?
No, no. You know the rules.
No girls allowed in your bedroom
unless one of us is upstairs.
So, we're just supposed to stay here,
hang out with your lame
old friends all night?
Sandra just spent 20 minutes telling us
how she installed her own
toilet. That's not fair.
No, what's not fair is when
I make you start cleaning up
all the dirty plates around the house,
because you just called
our friends lame and old.
Knock yourself out.
- Taking out the trash?
- Hey, enough. Go, go, go.
Lexi, you can help, please.
Why does she have to be here?
She is your brother's girlfriend.
Look, I know that this has got
to be hard for you right now,
- but she's your best friend.
- Not anymore.
Just like families,
sometimes friends fight.
And lie to your face?
And they still love you no matter what.
Yeah, well... if that's
love, I don't want it.
- Mariana!
- Oh, my God, Garret!
- Mariana, you look beautiful.
- Where are your mothers?
Kitchen.
Wow, you look... different.
Puberty. Turns out the rumor's
true. It really does change things.
That's what happens when we
don't see each other for a year.
What's happening with you? Tell
me everything. Max detail. Go.
Thank you for bringing the casserole.
- Vegetarian?
- Vegan.
We can barely get food on
the table three times a day.
I don't know how you guys
find time to be so healthy.
I don't do it. All credit
to the chef in the family.
- Where's Stef?
- She's out back, womaning the grill.
That's the nicest thing she's said
to me in I don't know how long.
We're going through a rough patch.
- We all go through those.
- Yeah, did they usually last two years?
Is everything ok?
We're talking about splitting up.
What?
No, that's impossible. You can't
do that, you're Kelly and Jenna.
I know.
After 20 years, you start
thinking it's really forever,
that nothing can pull you apart.
- So, what changed?
- I don't know.
We did, I guess. You know how it is,
you're so focused on kids,
work, and paying the bills,
that you stop paying
attention to each other.
All the things you used to do for
each other, the little stuff...
one day, you start
forgetting to do those things,
and you think, "It doesn't matter."
Then the next day,
you stop caring that you
forgot in the first place.
And before long, you realize all
you have in common is the routine.
And since I've been obsessed
with Ferlinghetti for a year,
I decided to try poetry.
So, I'm writing a piece
for a poetry slam this week.
What's a poetry slam?
It's sort of like a concert,
but with poems instead of songs.
Think hip-hop meets the Beat poets.
You know, Ginsberg and Kerouac.
Oh, yeah, I totally love them.
The art house in Hillcrest
is playing On the Road.
From the novel. You know, by Kerouac.
Oh, right.
- You want to check it out with me?
- Ok.
Having fun?
It's kind of a weird party.
Yeah, my moms have a lot of weird friends.
- I mean, everybody's nice.
- Hey.
Hey, what's he doing here?
I invited him.
- Hey.
Wow, this is quite the rager.
Lighten up, dude. I'm kidding.
Yeah, I know. Just don't call me dude.
Did you get enough to eat, Jude?
Yeah.
Ok, see this is a dry dish.
- And this is me not caring.
- Watch your mouth, young man.
What? If you like how he
does it so much better,
he can come over every night and do it.
So, Jenna told me that Garret
is doing some poetry slam.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I was thinking, maybe we could all go
if he makes it to performance round.
It'd be a nice break from
volleyball and television...
Might even learn something.
- I'm in.
- Ooh, learning. Cool.
- Wow.
- I'll go.
Not your thing?
No, no, just... yeah, it's not my thing.
Well, it's your choice, but
we'd love to have you join us.
If it's ok, I think I'm just gonna pass.
Ok, manual labor's done.
I got to get home. Thank
you, guys, for a fun night.
- Thank you for helping us.
- Very nice to meet you, Wyatt.
- Pleasure.
- Ok.
- Yeah, nice to meet you, Wyatt.
- You, too, big guy. See you.
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com
All right.
- Goodnight.
Hey, what are you doing with that guy?
That guy is the only
person I've met at school
who isn't completely freaked out by me.
Just be careful with him.
What's that supposed to mean?
- He used to date Talya.
- So?
It's not that. I mean...
Ok, he was really into her for awhile,
then he convinced her to have sex with him.
- Yeah?
- And then he dumped her.
The next day. Just trust
me, he's not a good guy.
Isn't it Jesus's week to help with laundry?
Yeah, I told him not to bother.
The last time he did
it my white linen pants
came out of the dryer as pink capris.
Yeah.
So, Jenna told me that she
and Kelly may be splitting up.
What? No way. What? You're kidding.
I know. Jenna said they
haven't had sex in over a year.
Oh, dear.
That is a long time to let it go, isn't it.
How long has it been for us?
Uh, it was last...
If you have to think about
it, it's been too long.
Sweetheart, what do you expect?
We have jobs, five kids,
and no cleaning person.
Can't expect things to be
the way they used to be.
They shouldn't be this different.
Let's have a date night.
You know, like we used to.
With cocktails, and dinner,
and then other stuff...
Mm-hm. You think we
have time for all that?
- How about just the "other stuff" part?
- I can handle that.
Let me check my phone.
Let's see.
- Tomorrow's not great.
- Why?
Jude has his tutor and you have to take
Brandon to his dentist appointment.
No, I thought you were taking Brandon.
No, I can't. I have to talk to
the tutor about Jude's mid-terms.
Ok, how about this? How about...
You leave work early, I will take a
late lunch. The house will be empty.
And there will be no kids to worry about.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Do we have any antacids? Your
chimichangas are killing me...
What time are your parents coming home?
Not for hours.
- Are you ok?
- I'm great, I just...
Just need a little break.
We don't have to stop.
Really?
I like that color.
Are you sure it's not too much?
I'm going for the "I'm being
carelessly casual but just happen
to be fabulous" look for my date tonight.
It's pretty.
Do you want me to do yours?
- Come on, let me do yours too.
- Ok.
So, anything new and
exciting in your world?
Made any new friends?
Well, there is this one boy.
- Oh?
- His name is Connor,
and we have math class together.
- What's he like?
- I don't know. He's pretty cool.
Uh, don't wear that to school. Ok, buddy?
You don't have to do
everything she says, you know...
What happened with you and Talya?
My night was great.
And yes, this is a new
shirt, thanks for noticing.
- It does bring out my eyes.
- Everything's not a joke.
Ok, wow, you're going
for this direct thing.
This is Brandon, right? He told you this?
Talya and I,
we hung out, she seemed chill,
I liked her, and we had sex.
And that's supposed to make you,
what exactly? Feel like a real man?
You wanted to know what happened.
I'm just giving you the full story.
As soon as we did it, she changed.
She got all weird and controlling.
In case you haven't noticed,
that's not really my thing.
So, after a couple weeks, I let
her know I wasn't into it anymore.
So, you didn't break up
with her the next day?
I did not. Everyone thinks
she's one of those nice girls,
she's actually kind of crazy.
Ah... sorry.
Apology not accepted.
What?
If you think you can just attack me...
- Wasn't an attack.
- ... and say you're sorry and it's all better?
Mm-mm. I'm not some pushover who
takes a hit and comes back for more.
You're going to have to make it up to me.
Tomorrow night.
And do what?
I don't know yet.
Well, I'll have to ask Lena and Stef.
They'll say yes.
So, you're confident.
Well, I didn't stick
around and dry their dishes
just because I like cleaning
up after other people.
See you tomorrow.
It was not.
I swear, it was a 55-pound white seabass.
My dad weighed it. It was crazy big.
- You fish?
- I've never even been on a boat.
How do you grow up by the
beach but never get on a boat?
You have to come next
time my dad takes me out.
- Really?
- Wait, I forgot my book.
- Nice nails.
- You wearing a bra, too?
Why don't you guys just grow up?
What'd you just say?
I said grow up, idiot.
- Who're you calling an idiot?
- What's going on here?
Blake, Jeremy. Principal's office. Now.
Hey. Brought you something.
They had the good ones
in the cafeteria today.
I know you like them, so...
Thanks.
Are you ok?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You sure?
What if I get pregnant?
- That's not going to happen.
- You don't know that.
My parents...
my parents would kill me.
Yes, I need a morning-after pill, please.
Thanks.
Hi. I'm picking up for
my son, Jesus Foster.
And this, please.
Hey!
What is going on?
- Lena?
- Upstairs!
Uh, I am here with Jesus.
Could you come down for a minute, please?
Why is Mom home so early?
You are not in a position
to be asking questions.
Hey, what's going on?
Last night, I...
last night, Lexi and I had sex.
Oh, my God.
Ok...
And?
And we didn't use protection.
How many times have we talked about this?
I know, but it... just sort of happened.
And then it was too late.
Well, we needed the morning-after pill,
but I guess you have to have ID to buy it.
Neither of us have ID, so...
I asked some lady at the
pharmacy to get the pill for us.
And that's when Mom found me.
Jesus, how many ways do we
have to tell you to come to us?
Why didn't you come to us?
To avoid this.
I don't know what to say.
So, can I give it to her?
Your mom and I need to talk about
this. Please go to your room.
I know it was stupid, but Lexi
thought it was the only thing to do.
- Why?
- She's afraid her parents are going to find out and freak.
We did everything we were supposed to do...
open dialogue, no stigmatizing,
no fear based warnings. We even
put condoms in their bathroom.
We can't blame ourselves, honey.
I know, I know. I'm just...
- Really disappointed.
- I know.
So, now what?
- We give her the pill.
- What about her parents?
What about her parents.
If this were Mariana,
we would want to know.
We can't go making decisions
for other people's kids.
Ok, what if she gets pregnant, Lena?
You know how religious her parents are.
They're certainly not
going to let her terminate.
They're going to want them to get married.
Do you want Jesus to be
married and a father at 15?
Please quit reminding me that they're 15.
- Well, they are.
- There's always adoption.
I... do you really want
them to go through that?
- 'Cause I got to tell you...
- I have a responsibility here.
I am her vice principal.
And I am not.
Can we just take a beat, please?
This is not the kind of thing we act on
without thinking it through first.
I'm going to go get dressed.
You didn't like it, did you.
Of course, I liked it.
On the Road is like a classic.
It's just... I don't know,
I feel like everyone was kind of selfish,
and just angry and didn't
care about anyone else.
They had a lot to be angry about.
They were looking for answers and
no one else was even asking the questions.
Ok, I guess I didn't like it.
Maybe next time we can
go see The Lone Ranger.
So, you want to come inside?
We can, I don't know,
watch TV or something.
TV's not really my thing.
Besides, I got to meet up with a friend.
I promised I'd help her rehearse a poem
for the first round of the Slam tomorrow.
The second round's
supposed to be a big to-do.
But, thanks for a fun time.
- Yeah, sure.
- See you later.
No, I'm serious.
It's like he didn't
even know it was a date.
Maybe he didn't. Why do you care anyway?
Well, we're not all as lucky as you.
You just got here, you don't even try,
and you already have a boyfriend.
Wyatt, not a boyfriend.
He sure seems like a boyfriend.
Look, if Garret wants to hang out
with some alternative
poetry girls, let him.
Besides, do you really want to date a guy
whose pants are tighter than yours?
They were kind of tight, huh?
How're you holding up?
I'm fine.
Do you want to talk about anything?
What's going on?
Jude just had a rough day yesterday.
Some of the kids were
giving him a hard time.
What happened? Are you ok?
He's fine. But, a couple of the
guys noticed his nail polish...
I told you not to go to
school with it on, Jude.
Go take it off. Now.
Stop telling me what to do.
Callie, Jude's a special kid.
I appreciate what you're
trying to do, Lena,
but what makes him
special, gets him beat up.
Well, he's safe in this house.
And thank you for that, really,
but we're not staying here.
I don't want him to start
thinking the world is like this,
and then we move, and
then he gets even more hurt
when he figures out that it's not.
- Hey. Hello.
- Hey, Wyatt.
Oh, wait, before you go.
It's an old one of Stef's.
We want you to have it.
You're on the family plan now.
- Thanks.
- So, 10 o'clock, and not a second later.
- Got it?
- Got it.
Oh, I'm glad to hear that,
but I wasn't talking to you.
Ten o'clock.
Yeah.
Where's she going?
On a date with Wyatt.
What about you? You got any plans?
Um... no.
So, when do I get to know
what we're actually doing here?
Wait and see.
Come on.
You have a beach house?
My parents do. Pretty much never use it.
Ok, what are we doing here?
You hear about that meteor shower tonight?
What about it?
Front row seats. Come on.
The sun's about to set.
May I?
You know, just a little
dab will do the trick.
Do you mind?
Ok.
When Stef and I are at home,
we hold hands and kiss...
Really?
Well, we used to do it a lot more often,
but we've just been really busy lately.
What does being busy have
to do with holding hands?
Ok, we're getting a little off-track here.
My point is,
sometimes when we're
out in a new neighborhood
or walking home late to our
car, we won't hold hands.
Why?
Some people out there
are afraid of what's different,
and sometimes they want to
hurt people like Stef and me.
So, every time we're out and
I want to hold Stef's hand,
but I decide not to?
I get mad.
I'm mad at the people
who might want to hurt us,
but mad at myself, too,
for not standing up to them.
'Cause the thing is,
if you're taught to hide
what makes you different,
you can end up feeling a lot
of shame about who you are,
and that's not ok.
There's nothing wrong with
you for wearing nail polish,
just like there's nothing wrong
with me for holding Stef's hand.
What's wrong is the people out
there who make us feel unsafe.
It's beautiful.
You mean that dense layer of clouds
that's keeping us from seeing anything
or the loud plane that keeps flying over?
- Well, you tried.
- I tried.
Valiant effort.
You have an eye booger.
Oh, my God... seriously?
No, I'm just making it up to
make you feel good about yourself.
- Other side.
- All right...
It's still there, you just moved it.
- Ok.
- I'll get it.
I thought you said your
parents never use the house.
Yeah, this isn't my house. We got to go.
What the hell was that?
I did a construction job
at that house last summer.
I really thought they only
used the place on weekends.
Are you freakin' kidding me?
I'm on probation! You understand
what could have happened
- if they caught us?
- I'm sorry...
I was just trying to impress you.
Well, congratulations.
I'm blown away by your utter lack
of regard for anyone but yourself.
I have to be home in a half hour.
Good luck getting through the
police barricade to get to my car.
It's too soon?
Hey.
And wisps of dirty hair
cling to your angry face
There is a tiny bit of mustard
burrowed in the crack of your frown
And this is when I know
And this is when it changes
And this is the way I will remember you
You seriously did great.
Like, Andrea Gibson great.
I couldn't have done it without you.
Hey, what are you doing here?
Um, I'm performing.
You kind of inspired me.
Oh, ok. That's great.
I'm sorry. Mariana, this is Savannah.
Savannah, this is Mariana.
She's a friend of my family.
I like your outfit, and
your poem was really cool.
Oh. Thanks.
Mom.
I'm guessing you're not here
for a little mother-son time?
Did you guys decide about the pill yet?
We're still thinking, Jesus.
Ok, but, Lexi's kind of
freaking out, because...
Well, it's called the morning-after
pill for a reason, you know?
Yes. I know.
This is one of those things
we'll laugh about tomorrow.
It's unlikely.
- Thanks for coming.
- Sure.
Thanks for bailing us out, bro.
I'm not your bro.
Blooming like a rose in spring
Blossoming like an Easter lily
Your smile is a flower on
the garden of your face.
Woo!
That was really nice.
- Thanks.
- All right.
Thank you so very much for coming.
We're impressed. So, for
tomorrow's round-two performance,
we'd like to use...
Matt DeVry, Alice Lewis,
Gabriella DuPont, Savannah
George, and Mo Peters...
and closing the night
out will be Garret Paul.
Let's give all the performers a hand.
Thanks for coming out.
- Sorry.
- It's cool.
Closing the show, huh? Nice.
Excuse me. Hi...
I was just wondering if you could
tell me why I didn't make it?
You know, so I can be better
prepared for next time.
This is your first performance, right?
You did an amazing job, really.
We're just looking for something different.
A little more raw, you
know? But you'll get there.
- Hey, I said I was sorry.
- And I said it was ok.
- Why are you acting so mad?
- You really have to ask?
You just had me pick you
up on a date with Wyatt!
Why do you hate Wyatt so much?
This isn't even about Wyatt.
Ok?
I don't want you dating Wyatt
because I don't want you dating anyone.
I can't...
- I can't do this.
- Well, too bad.
Even having this conversation could
get me and Jude kicked out of the house.
- That would never happen.
- You don't know that.
Two years ago, Jude and I were
in a really good foster home.
Definitely the best before coming here.
And they had a son.
And he was really nice to me.
So, we started hanging out.
And then the parents found out.
And he told them it was my fault,
I was coming on to him.
And the next day,
the next day, they had
me and Jude sent away.
And the parents told CPS some excuse.
They didn't want to admit
that their son was having
a relationship with the trashy foster girl.
So, yeah, Brandon. It can happen...
because it already did.
I'm not like him. I would never do that.
It doesn't matter. It
still ends the same way.
Admit it, you want me to apologize.
I don't, because it doesn't matter.
No, you do want me to
apologize so you can forgive me
and everything can go back
to normal because you like me.
So I like you because you're
reckless and presumptuous?
That's interesting.
You're not as good of a
liar as you think you are.
Look, I've done a lot of
stupid things in my life,
I haven't regretted any
of it, until last night.
I should not have done what I did.
I regret it. And I'm sorry.
So, how long are you going
to leave me hanging here?
We good?
Come on, it's not like
I'm asking you to marry me.
Just give me another chance, all right?
You ok?
These lips take a while to process, I know.
I'm fine.
Are you sure you're ok?
I'm not feeling great, but I'm ok. Yeah.
But, this... all of this is too much.
I think we need to...
well, stop doing what we did.
At least for a little while.
And if that means you don't like me...
Hey, hey.
I like you. I'm not going anywhere, ok?
Hey.
Want half? Their peanut
butter is all weird and oily
but it's still pretty
good if you add sugar.
Why are you still wearing that?
Because I like it.
Well, take it off before
you get a black eye to match.
- No.
- What?
I'm not taking it off.
You want to get beat up again?
Yeah, that's exactly what I want.
Look, I know it's easy
to feel comfortable here,
but this isn't our home.
You shouldn't get too
invested in these people.
Why not? Don't you want a family?
- I have a family.
- It's not...
I like them. They're nice.
And maybe it's not forever, but so what?
You're going to get hurt.
I already hurt.
Sorry to bother you. Do you have a minute?
Of course. Come on in.
Have a seat.
What's up?
I just wanted to tell you that
I'm sorry if I disappointed you.
You and Stef have been
a second family to me.
Have you thought any more
about talking to your mom?
Oh. No, I can't. She'd lose it.
I mean, if she ever found out
that you guys gave me the pill,
she'd go crazy.
My mom can get so mad.
Your mom's not the only one.
Ok...
I just wanted to say thank you.
- You'll tell Stef for me?
- Oh, I definitely will.
Were you going to tell me?
I was, when you got home.
Can we please talk in here.
Well, instead I had to
learn from a 15 year old girl
that my partner went behind my back.
I'm sorry, but I knew
you felt a responsibility
to Lexi's parents because
you're her vice principal.
I did it so you did not have to.
- How generous.
- That's not productive.
We make decisions about
our children together.
Yes, absolutely we do.
But waiting to make a decision could
have made our son a father at 15.
I knew you were in an awkward
position. I was very careful.
I talked her through everything,
and I made sure she knew
this was a last resort.
Tell me you're not relieved, Lena.
Hey, we've been waiting
for you. We got to go...
We're gonna be late. Everybody
please come downstairs.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Where's Mariana?
Probably sticking pins
in a voodoo doll of Lexi.
- Hey, cool it. You owe us.
- I'm sorry.
Yeah, cool it...
Who you telling to cool it?
Will you go get her, please?
- Why do I have to go?
- Because you're our favorite.
Hey... is it too late for me to tag along?
No, of course not. We'd love it.
Mariana, you in there?
Mariana?
Moms are going to kill you.
Nice of you to join us, Miss Thing.
What happened to your face?
- Do you like it?
- No, I don't like it.
- Did it hurt?
- Sort of.
Of course it hurt. You
punched a hole in your face.
Ok, enough. We'll deal with you later.
Let's go. Everybody in the car.
What is happening?
What's happening?
Last Tuesday night,
my mother Jenna comes into the house
I'm sitting in the living
room with my other mom, Kelly.
Jenna asks us if we'll take a drive
with her, so we all get in the car.
And as we drive, silence creeps along
like the cracks in a frozen lake.
Our hearts begin to thud slowly,
off beat.
And I wonder and then I know.
And I didn't imagine
it would end like this.
I didn't imagine an ending at all,
but if they were going to
tell me about the divorce,
what a way to do it.
I sit in the backseat and think about
how lucky we were to have had this family.
Their 20 years of
marriage, my 15 with them.
I remember all of us, driving
for miles out on the highway
until I fell asleep in the backseat.
I don't want this life to
end, Jenna starts to talk.
She tells me that our car
is just 13 miles away from
reaching 100,000 miles now.
I wonder if this is part of the
divorce speech or just a distraction.
I feel angry, they should just say it.
She tells me the reason we took this ride
is so that we could all be there
to reach 100,000 miles together,
as the people who matter in her life.
Slowly, I realize that
this isn't a breakup ride
or a divorce ride, or a separation ride.
This is a 100,000 mile ride.
We're in the car, and we're
driving on a Tuesday night,
and we're 99,987 miles in.
We stop for onion rings
and sundaes, keep driving.
99,993 miles, Stevie Nicks.
99,997 miles, Elton John.
When we get to 999,999 miles we hold hands,
blast Melissa Etheridge, and sing
Lucky at the top of our lungs.
There are too many reasons that my mamas
found love in each other's presence.
There are too many moments
when we are unbreakable,
and in this moment, we are one family.
Constructing road as we go,
burning bridges behind us,
adding mileage like graceful aging.
Driving in our car towards moonlight.
All right, Garret! Woo!
Hey. Congrats. You
totally blew everyone away.
Aw, thanks.
At least we got the happy
ending for one night.
What do you mean?
My moms are splitting up.
They don't think I know.
- Oh, my God. I'm sorry...
- Me, too.
- What's up with the face art?
- You like?
Yeah, why'd you do it?
I don't know. Just trying something new.
You know, a little edgier.
You don't have to try so hard.
You're already pretty great.
Will be in in a minute, you guys.
So, they're really getting a divorce?
They really are.
Oh, my God. I can't imagine.
- Thank God.
- What?
I mean, "Thank God you can't imagine."
- Mm.
- I can't either.
I thought they would be
together forever, you know...
I guess everybody thinks
that when they start a family.
I'm sorry about the way
I handled the pill thing.
- Not the giving it part...
- Thank you.
I'm sorry I forgot to buy your guacamole.
- You really are a saint.
- Pretty much.
- A hot saint.
- Really?
Oh, yeah.
- Wait, we can't do this.
- Why not?
The kids are right inside.
They're going to come
looking for us? Please.
Why don't we take this
somewhere more comfortable?
Ok... hold up, my foot's stuck.
Stop! Sh...
- synced and corrected by chamallow -
akumenang.com